<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" >

<channel>
	<title>Crisis Resolutions</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/plus-stream/video/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Ai Enhanced Good Governance Gamification</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 21:29:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<itunes:subtitle>Crisis Resolutions</itunes:subtitle>
	<itunes:summary>Ai Enhanced Good Governance Gamification</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
	<item>
		<title>8. Empirical Science</title>
		<link>/personal-continence-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 12:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=2572</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Science is a method of empirical inquiry that can help us achieve freedom, diversity, inclusion, fitness, and wellbeing.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/personal-continence-3/">8. Empirical Science</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Crisis Resolutions Training -  Ep07 - Science" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NG5SJLR6LEE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong>Crisis Resolutions Video Training &#8211; Episode 7</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Episode 7</strong> Narrative</h2>



<p>Episode 7 explores our Empirical Good Ways and how they relate to the practice of science.</p>



<p>Science is a method of empirical inquiry that can help us achieve freedom, diversity, inclusion, fitness, and wellbeing.</p>



<p>Through cooperation and the investigation of science, we can develop a deeper understanding of the world around us and make more informed decisions, ultimately leading to personal growth and fulfilling lives.</p>



<p>Additionally, by passing on the methods and practices of good crisis resolution to future generations, we can help them better understand and address crises as they arise.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Ways of Science Genesis</h3>



<p>Science is a method of empirical inquiry that helps us maintain flexibility of freedom, diversity, inclusion, fitness, partying, and wellbeing. By analyzing input feedback, indexing evaluation, output feedback, modeling classification, and memory allocation, we can sustain economic liberty, ecophysiological equality, ecological solidarity, ecospheric peace, ecotypic order, and ecosystemic governance. Then, through cooperation in matters of accessibility levels empowerment, topics support, recipes composition, journals documentation, challenges adaptation, and rituals coexistence we can refine our capability for self-reflection genesis, sentience practice, self-autonomy mimesis, simplicity growth, symmetry investigation, and variety inheritance.</p>



<p>For individual practices, one example is the process of self-reflection, which can help us better understand our thoughts, feelings, and behaviors. Another is the practice of empathy, which helps us understand and connect with others on a deeper level.</p>



<p>For family practices, one example is the modeling of self-autonomy, which encourages family members to make decisions for themselves and take responsibility for their actions. This can lead to a stronger sense of independence and self-confidence.</p>



<p>In professional settings, the practice of sentience can be beneficial. This means being aware of and responsive to one&#8217;s own feelings and the feelings of others. It can lead to better communication and collaboration within a team.</p>



<p>Finally, for social practices, exploring symmetry can be helpful. This involves investigating patterns and relationships in the world around us, and can lead to a deeper understanding of how things work and how we can create more balance and harmony in the world.</p>



<p>By incorporating these practices into our daily lives, we can develop a better understanding of ourselves and others, and be better equipped to handle crises when they arise.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Times of Science Practice</h3>



<p>The practice of science can lead to good times such as intellectual discovery, personal growth, and the development of new technologies that benefit society.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Life of Science Mimesis</h3>



<p>The mimesis of science can contribute to a good life by promoting self-autonomy, sentience, and self-reflection. By developing a deeper understanding of the world around us, we can make more informed decisions and live more fulfilling lives.</p>



<p>The inheritance of science includes the transfer of knowledge, skills, and abilities from one generation to the next. By passing on the methods and practices of good crisis resolution, we can help future generations to better understand and address crises as they arise.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/personal-continence-3/">8. Empirical Science</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>0. Crisis Resolutions Video Training Introduction</title>
		<link>/crisis-resolutions-video-training-intro/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 11:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=2537</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This course is a documentation of our code of ethics, and provides a framework for resolving any kind of human-sustained crisis.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/crisis-resolutions-video-training-intro/">0. Crisis Resolutions Video Training Introduction</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Crisis Resolutions Training -  Introduction" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xqYOGclAxA4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong>Crisis Resolutions Video Training &#8211; Introduction</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Narrative</h2>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><strong>Crisis &#8211; The Common Source of Origination of Everything.</strong></p>



<p>Hello, and Welcome.</p>



<p>Crisis is a difficult and troubling situation that often serves as a catalyst for change and the beginning of something new. It can be the source of great stress and uncertainty, yet also offers an opportunity to look at a problem from a different perspective and take action to create positive transformation. In times of crisis, it is important to remember that we can still take control of our lives, and make meaningful progress, even when the future is uncertain.</p>



<p>Everything may be in crisis, and while it can be overwhelming, it&#8217;s important to remember that the source of the crisis is always one. Identifying and addressing this source is difficult, but it&#8217;s the only path to relief. All other measures are temporary solutions.</p>



<p>The curriculum of Crisis Resolutions is based on the principle of good crisis, or in simple words, of good thinking. It consists of 9 chapters, which focus on understanding the source of the crisis and how to achieve relief.</p>



<p>Moreover, we promote good governance policies and sustainable development goals compliance.</p>



<p>This course is a documentation of our code of ethics, and provides a framework for resolving any kind of human-sustained crisis.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p>Good Ways Training is a comprehensive program that focuses on the mastery of:</p>



<ul>
<li>Good Flexibility through Character Management,</li>



<li>Good Sensibility through Intelligence Curation,</li>



<li>Good Sustainability through Services Interaction,</li>



<li>Good Accessibility through Community Cooperation,</li>



<li>and Good Capability through Systems Operation.</li>
</ul>



<p>The program is designed to help individuals understand the common source of all sorts of good ways and apply them to daily life, including governance.</p>



<p>Each episode offers an introduction to its respective topic, explores the concept, and provides practical guidance on how to incorporate good ways into personal and professional life.</p>



<p>This program emphasizes the importance of practicing good ways to overcome challenges and achieve well-being.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p>Everything is rooted in a common source, and all crises can be traced back to this source.</p>



<p>This source is the foundation of all life, and it is the source of all solutions. It is a source of understanding, of wisdom, and of compassion.</p>



<p>Through our understanding of this source, we can identify the causes of any crisis, and develop strategies to resolve it.</p>



<p>We can leverage this opportunity to collaboratively construct a world that is just and fair. By identifying the common good in any crisis, we can foster positive change for all.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p>This program emphasizes the importance of practicing good ways to overcome challenges and achieve well-being.</p>



<p>You don&#8217;t need to remember the Good Ways Model, as all episodes have been designed to present information in a simple, systematic, and repetitive way. Therefore, you won&#8217;t need to take notes.</p>



<p>You can further study the Model and Practice by examining it directly, rather than trying to remember it.</p>



<p>We learn and master the Good Ways Model through personal and cooperative practice, which reflects our natural capabilities.</p>



<p>While our model can be a helpful tool, it&#8217;s not a prerequisite for practicing Good Ways and resolving crises.</p>



<p><em>This publication is designed to provide accurate and authoritative information in regard to the subject matter covered. If expert assistance or counseling is needed, the services of a professional should be sought.</em></p>



<p>Tags: crisis, change, problem-solving, personal development, good governance, sustainability, well-being, character management, intelligence curation, community cooperation, systems operation, compassion, justice</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/crisis-resolutions-video-training-intro/">0. Crisis Resolutions Video Training Introduction</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>1. About Good Ways</title>
		<link>/about-good-ways/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 11:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=2558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Good Ways are essential to promoting positive communication, collaboration, and understanding between individuals with different values, beliefs, technologies, policies, and intentions.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/about-good-ways/">1. About Good Ways</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Crisis Resolutions Training -  Ep00 - Good Ways" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tyatRqQ0guc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong>Crisis Resolutions Video Training &#8211; Episode</strong> <strong>0</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Episode 0 Narrative</h2>



<p>The beginning of Crisis Resolutions&#8217; training series focuses on the genesis and growth of &#8220;Good Ways&#8221;.</p>



<p>The Good Ways Standards provide a model to measure, comprehend, and manage human capacity and capabilities, with 8 Standard Good Ways and 205 Dependent Good Ways.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Good Ways Genesis</h2>



<p>Good Ways are essential to promoting positive communication, collaboration, and understanding between individuals with different values, beliefs, technologies, policies, and intentions.</p>



<p>They serve as an effective tool for managing and measuring our human capacity and capabilities. The Good Ways Standards provide a model that allows individuals to comprehend and manage their interactions with others in a way that is respectful, honest, and empathetic.</p>



<p>The Good Ways Standards comprise of eight Standard Good Ways, each responsible for their own families of ways organized in sets of Indices. These families of ways offer a comprehensive mapping of human intelligence through the 8 Standard and 205 Dependent Good Ways. Each Good Way is self-explanatory, symmetrically related, and can be easily remembered through association with parts of our body, which is the most ancient and advanced form of learning.</p>



<p>The position of each Good Way in the list is significant, and each one describes a different measure of complexity of a same-numbered-one from another list. By understanding the different measures of complexity of each Good Way, individuals can better comprehend how to interact with others in a way that is respectful, empathetic, and considerate of different perspectives.</p>



<p>Examples of personal, professional, and social practice of Good Ways could include practicing active listening in personal relationships, using ethical decision-making frameworks in the workplace to promote fairness and equity, and promoting diversity and inclusion initiatives in the community to foster greater understanding and collaboration among individuals from different backgrounds.</p>



<p>By embracing Good Ways in our personal, professional, and social lives, we can build stronger relationships, promote greater understanding, and create a more harmonious and inclusive world.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Good Times Practice</h2>



<p>Good Times Practice is a way of applying the principles of Good Ways in everyday life. It involves consciously seeking out opportunities to create positive experiences for oneself and others.</p>



<p>By focusing on the good in life, we can cultivate a more positive and optimistic outlook, which can help us to better cope with the challenges and crises that we face.</p>



<p>The investigation of Good Times involves exploring the elements that contribute to a positive and fulfilling life. This can include factors such as personal growth, meaningful relationships, and a sense of purpose or fulfillment. By examining these elements and understanding what brings us happiness and satisfaction, we can work to cultivate and maintain them in our lives.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Good Life Mimesis</h2>



<p>The mimesis of a good life is a complex process that involves more than just superficially adopting certain values and principles. To truly embody the Good Ways Model, it is necessary to engage in a comprehensive practice of flexibility, sensibility, sustainability, accessibility, and capability throughout all aspects of our daily lives.</p>



<p>For instance, flexibility does not just mean being adaptable to changing circumstances, but also being open-minded to new ideas, perspectives, and experiences. Sensibility involves not only being aware of our own emotions and needs, but also being empathetic towards other people&#8217;s feelings and concerns. Sustainability encompasses not only environmental conservation practices, but also responsible consumption and ethical business practices. Accessibility entails not only physical accessibility for people with disabilities, but also social and economic accessibility for marginalized communities. Finally, capability means not only developing our own personal skills and abilities, but also empowering others to achieve their full potential.</p>



<p>By taking a more holistic approach to the Good Ways Model, we can truly integrate these values and principles into our daily lives and make a positive impact on ourselves and the world around us.</p>



<p>Good Life Inheritance is the idea of passing down the essential elements of a good life to future generations. It involves understanding what truly matters in life and recognizing that we have a shared responsibility to ensure that these elements are passed on to future generations. One important aspect of this idea is understanding the origins of a good life.</p>



<p>By exploring and reflecting on the origins of a good life, we can gain insight into what is truly important and necessary for a meaningful and fulfilling life. This involves examining both the physical and metaphysical origins of a good life. The physical origins may include factors such as the environment, the time in which a person lives or lived, the resources available, and the people involved in their life. The metaphysical origins may include factors such as purpose, meaning, values, and beliefs.</p>



<p>When we understand the origins of a good life, we can better appreciate the importance of certain elements, such as love, compassion, kindness, and resilience. By recognizing these elements as essential components of a good life, we can work to ensure that future generations inherit them. This involves actively teaching and modeling these elements to our children and future generations, as well as advocating for social structures and policies that support them.</p>



<p>Furthermore, understanding the origins of a good life can help us identify the source of any crisis we may face in our lives or in society as a whole. By recognizing the root cause of a problem, we can work collaboratively to find solutions that are consistent with the essential elements of a good life. This approach can help ensure that future generations inherit a world that is more just, equitable, and sustainable.</p>



<p>In summary, understanding the origins of a good life is a crucial component of Good Life Inheritance. By exploring and reflecting on the physical and metaphysical origins of a good life, we can gain insight into what is truly important and necessary for a fulfilling life. We can then work collaboratively to ensure that future generations inherit these essential elements, and create a better future for all.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/about-good-ways/">1. About Good Ways</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2. Personal Continence</title>
		<link>/personal-continence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 12:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=2567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The beginning of Crisis Resolutions' training series focuses on the genesis and growth of "Good Ways".</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/personal-continence/">2. Personal Continence</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Crisis Resolutions Training -  Ep01 - Continence" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eCg_1jok2N0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong>Crisis Resolutions Video Training &#8211; Episode 1</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Episode 1 Narrative</h2>



<p>The beginning of Crisis Resolutions&#8217; training series focuses on the genesis and growth of &#8220;Good Ways&#8221;.</p>



<p>The Good Ways Standards provide a model to measure, comprehend, and manage human capacity and capabilities, with 8 Standard Good Ways and 205 Dependent Good Ways.</p>



<p>In episode 1 of this training, we cover the topic of &#8220;Good Continence&#8221;. This concept applies to personal, professional, family, and social practices. We provide examples of each. In conclusion, we emphasize the importance of understanding crisis and consciousness.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Ways of Continence Genesis</h3>



<p>Personal Good Ways related to continence are methods that express the 1st level of flexibility, sensibility, sustainability, accessibility, and capability.</p>



<p>Continence as a personal practice involves flexibility in selfhood, childhood, parenthood, siblinghood, and spousehood. It involves sensitivity to capacity, charge, current, resistance, and power, and sustaining infinity, intensity, density, resistance, and conductivity. Continence also involves accessibility to probability, correlation, curvature, clustering, and causality. Finally, it involves capability through potential action, kinetic action, radiant action, thermal action, and chemical action.</p>



<p>Examples of personal good ways related to continence include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Selfhood Flexibility</strong>: Being open to new experiences and perspectives, and being willing to change one&#8217;s beliefs or opinions.</li>



<li><strong>Siblinghood Sensibility</strong>: Being aware of the needs and feelings of one&#8217;s siblings, and showing empathy and support.</li>



<li><strong>Parenthood Sustainability</strong>: Making responsible and sustainable choices for one&#8217;s children, such as choosing environmentally-friendly products and supporting ethical companies.</li>



<li><strong>Spousehood Accessibility</strong>: Communicating openly and honestly with one&#8217;s partner, and being receptive to their needs and desires.</li>



<li><strong>Childhood Capability</strong>: Developing the ability to delay gratification and control impulses, which can lead to greater success and happiness later in life.</li>
</ul>



<p>Good Ways of Continence Growth refer to the practices and actions we can take to develop the ability to control our impulses and desires.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Times of Continence Practice</h3>



<p>By practicing continence, we can learn to control our impulses and make more deliberate and thoughtful decisions.</p>



<p>One way to practice continence in our personal lives is by setting goals and working to achieve them. By focusing on our long-term objectives, we can resist the temptation to indulge in short-term pleasures that might distract us from our goals.</p>



<p>Example: Setting a goal to read one book per week and resisting the temptation to watch TV instead.</p>



<p>In a professional setting, practicing continence might mean resisting the urge to take shortcuts or make hasty decisions. Instead, we can take the time to carefully consider our options and make choices that are in line with our goals.</p>



<p>Example: Taking the time to conduct thorough research before making a business decision.</p>



<p>In a family setting, practicing continence might mean setting boundaries and being mindful of our interactions with others. By exercising self-control and showing restraint, we can cultivate stronger and more supportive relationships with our loved ones.</p>



<p>Example: Refraining from speaking harshly to a family member during a disagreement.</p>



<p>In a social setting, practicing continence might mean resisting peer pressure and making choices that align with our values and beliefs. By staying true to ourselves and exercising restraint, we can build stronger and more meaningful connections with others.</p>



<p>Example: Declining an invitation to engage in behavior that conflicts with our personal values.</p>



<p>Good Times can result from the investigation of Continence, as we learn to exercise self-restraint and discipline in our actions and decisions. This can lead to a sense of accomplishment and increased self-esteem, as we set and achieve goals for ourselves. For example, practicing self-control in our diet and exercise habits can lead to improved physical health and a sense of pride in our ability to make positive changes in our lives. In a professional setting, exercising restraint in our interactions with colleagues and clients can lead to improved relationships and increased success in our work. In a family setting, practicing Continence through effective communication and conflict resolution can lead to a stronger and more harmonious family dynamic, resulting in more good times and happy memories. Similarly, in a social setting, exercising self-control and discipline in our behavior can lead to stronger relationships and a more positive impact on those around us, ultimately resulting in more fulfilling and enjoyable social experiences.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Life of Continence Mimesis</h3>



<p>The mimesis of continence can result in a good life characterized by self-control, discipline, and moderation.</p>



<p>Good Life as a result of the Inheritance of Continence signifies the importance of understanding crisis and its effect on our lives. Crisis originally meant division and decision in ancient Greece, while in later centuries it was influenced by negative-reinforcement cultures and ended up reflecting guilt and endless punishment. In general, crisis denotes a momentum of great importance and is nothing else than a different word for the so-called intellect (thinking, data, cognition, conscience).</p>



<p>The fruits of crisis are always both pleasurable and painful at the same time, as we all inherit great powers in a very fragile state of living. It is up to us to focus on it as a moment of disaster and fear, or a moment to show our power for good judgment (humane sensibility, balance, middle way, manners, good ways).</p>



<p>A crisis is considered good when it takes the form of true self-judgment (altruism, empathy, non-biased sensible thinking). A bad crisis, on the other hand, turns to be a sense of depression through an addiction to self-regenerative judgment (the intellect bias, and our capability to think endlessly for the sake of thinking and therefore judging). This leads to a constant sense of lack of safety, which is what we call fear and sorrow.</p>



<p>Thinking is one of our greatest innovations, but also a trap of attentiveness which burdens us continuously and everyday for our whole lives. This capability of crisis to become a memory, which is a lasting form of crisis &#8211; magnetizing our attention according to our present conditions &#8211; is a gifted skill, but not the gift&#8217;s giver. So thinking and the intellect cannot define the source of crisis, which is the self.</p>



<p>In simple words, all forms of recorded knowledge, either traditional, esoteric, epistemic or whatever, are a very precious visualization of human complexity and identity &#8211; but at the same time have no power to define humans. As this is also what we have witnessed through the loss of common memory of generations of humans who came before our recorded history.</p>



<p>When sentience though gets liberated from the intellect &#8211; it becomes timeless (loses sense of time/troubles/pain/ego/self) &#8211; and signifies a state of receptive and proactive intelligence (revelation of what is) which is general and common to all life.</p>



<p>As long as we think (self-reflect), we will always be in crisis. Whenever our intellect silences (limits of mind) &#8211; we find that it is only our intelligent sensibility that remains (substratum, intuitive logic, true self, being, consciousness, spirituality, mindfulness, mortality, morality, ethics).</p>



<p>The Intellect Loop Bias is an unhealthy behavior that can lead to passive depression and aggression, ultimately resulting in a lack of mental stability and well-being. It is a common mental issue that affects the majority of the population and can manifest in a variety of ways, such as stress, anxiety, and feelings of hopelessness. With the right support and understanding, we can take control of our mental health and move beyond the intellect Loop Bias.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/personal-continence/">2. Personal Continence</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3. Mental Conscience</title>
		<link>/mental-conscience/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 12:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=2569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Episode 2 discusses the importance and benefits of practicing and investigating one's conscience.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/mental-conscience/">3. Mental Conscience</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Crisis Resolutions Training -  Ep02 - Conscience" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-nI3Vl10_PA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong>Crisis Resolutions Video Training &#8211; Episode</strong> <strong>2</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Episode 2 Narrative</h2>



<p>Episode 2 discusses the importance and benefits of practicing and investigating one&#8217;s conscience.</p>



<p>Good Ways of Conscience involve being flexible, sensible, sustainable, accessible, and capable. Living in accordance with our conscience can lead to a good life, free from afflictions such as ignorance, egoism, attachment, aversion, and the desire to cling to life. Practicing conscience can also lead to a greater sense of fulfillment and contentment with our actions and decisions, while investigating our conscience can lead to new insights and perspectives on life.</p>



<p>Additionally, cultivating gratitude and forgiveness can help develop a stronger sense of empathy and compassion towards ourselves and others.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Ways of Conscience Genesis</h3>



<p>Good Ways of Conscience have their origins in being flexible in terms of non-selfhood, non-childhood, non-parenthood, non-siblinghood, and non-spousehood. They also involve being sensible about non-capacitance, non-charge, non-current, non-resistivity, and non-power. Additionally, they require sustainability in terms of non-infinity, non-intensity, non-density, non-resistance, and non-conductivity. Furthermore, accessibility to non-probability, non-correlation, non-curvature, non-clustering, and non-causality is necessary. Finally, capability in terms of non-potential action, non-kinetic action, non-radiant action, non-thermal action, and non-chemical action is also required.</p>



<p><strong>Example Practices</strong>:</p>



<ul>
<li>Personal: Being flexible and adaptable to different situations and people</li>



<li>Professional: Being open to new ideas and ways of working</li>



<li>Family: Being understanding and supportive of family members&#8217; needs and feelings</li>



<li>Social: Being respectful and considerate of others&#8217; opinions and beliefs</li>
</ul>



<p>There are many ways to grow our conscience, including meditation, yoga, and mindfulness. In addition to these, cultivating gratitude and forgiveness can also help us develop a stronger sense of empathy and compassion towards ourselves and others.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Times of Conscience Practice</h3>



<p>When we practice conscience, we can experience a greater sense of fulfillment and contentment with our actions and decisions. It allows us to live more intentionally and make choices that align with our values and beliefs.</p>



<p>Investigating our conscience can lead to new insights and perspectives on life. By reflecting on our thoughts, emotions, and behaviors, we can gain a deeper understanding of ourselves and our place in the world.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Life of Conscience Mimesis</h3>



<p>Living in accordance with our conscience can lead to a good life, one that is free from the afflictions of ignorance, egoism, attachment, aversion, and the desire to cling to life. By living in a way that aligns with our values and beliefs, we can experience greater peace and harmony within ourselves and with those around us.</p>



<p>Inheriting a strong sense of conscience can lead to a good life that involves not only practicing self-restraint in actions such as abstaining from violence, falsehoods, stealing, and sexual misconduct, but also actively seeking opportunities to help others and make a positive impact on the world.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/mental-conscience/">3. Mental Conscience</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>4. Practical Presence</title>
		<link>/personal-continence-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 12:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=2576</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The third episode focuses on the importance of being present and aware in order to cultivate practical good ways that can help resolve crises.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/personal-continence-2/">4. Practical Presence</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Crisis Resolutions Training -  Ep03 - Presence" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uOvJwhF-Css?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong>Crisis Resolutions Video Training &#8211; Episode</strong> <strong>3</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Episode 3 Narrative</h2>



<p>The third episode focuses on the importance of being present and aware in order to cultivate practical good ways that can help resolve crises.</p>



<p>Being present and aware can lead to the development of practical good ways that can help individuals resolve crises more effectively.</p>



<p>By being fully engaged in the present moment, individuals can better understand the situation at hand and respond in a more effective and appropriate manner.</p>



<p>The practical good ways discussed, such as flexibility, sensibility, sustainability, accessibility, and capability, can be applied in various settings to help individuals navigate difficult situations and find positive outcomes.</p>



<p>Additionally, practicing presence can lead to a greater appreciation for life and a deeper understanding of oneself and the world around them, which can further contribute to personal growth and the development of positive relationships with others.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Ways of Presence Genesis</h3>



<p>The Genesis of Good Ways of Presence involves the development of practical good ways that help individuals be present and aware. These practical good ways can be applied in personal, professional, family, and social settings. The five categories of practical good ways are as follows:</p>



<p><strong>Practical Flexibility</strong>: Being flexible in a work setting when there are sudden changes to a project.</p>



<p><strong>Practical Sensibility</strong>: Being honest with a friend about how their actions have hurt you.</p>



<p><strong>Practical Sustainability</strong>: Creating a sustainable business model that can support the company for years to come.</p>



<p><strong>Practical Accessibility</strong>: Paying attention to a lecture in order to retain the information being presented.</p>



<p><strong>Practical Capability</strong>: Reacting quickly to a situation that requires immediate attention.</p>



<p>The growth of Good Ways of Presence involves the continued cultivation and development of practical good ways. This can be achieved through regular practice and application of these methods.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Times of Presence Practice</h3>



<p>Good times can be experienced as a result of practicing presence. By being present and aware, individuals can fully engage in experiences and appreciate the moment. Good times can be found in everyday moments, such as spending time with loved ones, enjoying a favorite hobby, or simply taking a moment to appreciate nature.</p>



<p>Good times can also be experienced as a result of investigating the concept of presence. By exploring what it means to be present and how to cultivate practical good ways, individuals can gain a deeper understanding of themselves and the world around them. This investigation can lead to personal growth and a greater appreciation for life.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Life of Presence Mimesis</h3>



<p>The Good Life of Presence involves incorporating practical good ways into daily life in order to cultivate a sense of purpose and fulfillment. By mimicking the presence and awareness of these good ways, individuals can create a life that is grounded in positivity and meaning.</p>



<p>The inheritance of the principles of Good Ways of Presence involves passing on the methods and practices of flexibility, sensibility, sustainability, accessibility, and capability to future generations. By doing so, a legacy of ethical behavior and positive relationships can be created, benefitting society as a whole.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/personal-continence-2/">4. Practical Presence</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5. Social Sense</title>
		<link>/social-sense/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 12:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=2575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Having a good sense of things can be beneficial in many ways. It can result in a more meaningful and ethical way of living.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/social-sense/">5. Social Sense</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Crisis Resolutions Training -  Ep04 - Sense" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DUrGbWitVZE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong>Crisis Resolutions Video Training &#8211; Episode 4</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Episode 4 Narrative</h2>



<p>In Episode 4 the focus is on how practicing Good Ways of Sense can help us be more flexible, adaptable, and able to handle situations with greater ease.</p>



<p>Having a good sense of things can be beneficial in many ways. It can result in a more meaningful and ethical way of living.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Ways of Sense Genesis</h3>



<p>Good Ways of Sense are methods related to our sense. They express the 4th level of our flexibility, sensibility, sustainability, accessibility, and capability.</p>



<p>For personal practice, an example is having the flexibility to detach oneself from emotions or circumstances and maintain an objective view.</p>



<p>For professional practice, an example is having the sustainability to have capacity, magnitude, coverage, formation, and convertibility.</p>



<p>For family practice, an example is having the capability of ethical conduct, effort, resolve, view, and livelihood.</p>



<p>For social practice, an example is having the accessibility to courage, receptiveness, altruism, truthfulness, and wisdom.</p>



<p>The growth of Good Ways of Sense involves practicing the methods related to our sense, which can lead to good times and a good life.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Times of Sense Practice</h3>



<p>Having good times as a result of practicing Sense involves being able to detach oneself from emotions or circumstances and maintain an objective view, and having the flexibility of detachment.</p>



<p>Having good times as a result of investigating Sense involves having the sensibility of hearing, touch, taste, vision, and smell. This can lead to good times as we are able to experience the world around us in a more profound and meaningful way.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Life of Sense Mimesis</h3>



<p>Having a good life as a result of mimicking Sense involves having the sustainability of capacity, magnitude, coverage, formation, and convertibility.</p>



<p>This can lead to a good life as we are able to live our lives in a more meaningful and ethical way.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/social-sense/">5. Social Sense</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>6. Ethical Absence</title>
		<link>/ethical-absence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 12:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=2574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Good Ways of Absence refer to the practice of being absent from certain behaviors, thoughts, or emotions that are deemed negative or unethical.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/ethical-absence/">6. Ethical Absence</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Crisis Resolutions Training -  Ep05 - Absence" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uZXqbY4JMEw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong>Crisis Resolutions Video Training &#8211; Episode</strong> <strong>5</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Episode 5 Narrative</h2>



<p>In this episode, we will explore the concept of Good Ways of Absence.</p>



<p>Good Ways of Absence refer to the practice of being absent from certain behaviors, thoughts, or emotions that are deemed negative or unethical. By abstaining from such behaviors, one can foster ethical behavior and positive relationships. It can lead to personal growth, increased self-awareness and self-discipline, and mutual respect and trust in relationships.</p>



<p>Practicing Good Ways of Absence can also lead to a sense of inner peace and satisfaction, healthy communication, and positive interactions. Living a life of Good Ways of Absence can inspire others to do the same, leading to a legacy of ethical behavior and positive relationships.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Ways of Absence Genesis</h3>



<p>Good Ways of Absence stem from the principle of being absent from certain behaviors, thoughts, or emotions. One example of Good Ways of Absence in personal practice could be abstaining from gossip or negative talk. In professional practice, it could be avoiding unethical business practices. In family practice, it could be refraining from blaming or shaming others. In social practice, it could be avoiding harmful stereotypes or biases.</p>



<p><strong>Ethical Flexibility:</strong></p>



<p>Ethical Flexibility involves being flexible without the need for detachment, perfection, imagination, imperfection, or memory. It is the ability to adjust and adapt to changing circumstances or conditions without compromising ethical behavior.</p>



<p><strong>Ethical Sensibility:</strong></p>



<p>Ethical Sensibility involves being sensible without the need for hearing, touch, taste, vision, or smell. It is the capacity to perceive, feel, or be conscious of something without relying on the senses.</p>



<p><strong>Ethical Sustainability:</strong></p>



<p>Ethical Sustainability involves being sustainable without the need for capacity, magnitude, coverage, formation, or convertibility. It is the ability to support and maintain oneself without depleting natural resources.</p>



<p><strong>Ethical Accessibility:</strong></p>



<p>Ethical Accessibility involves being accessible without the need for courage, receptiveness, altruism, truthfulness, or wisdom. It is the ability to access or use something, such as a resource or service, without compromising ethical behavior.</p>



<p><strong>Ethical Capability:</strong></p>



<p>Ethical Capability involves being capable through sensibility over the existence of non-ethical conduct, non-ethical effort, non-ethical resolve, non-ethical view, and non-ethical livelihood. It is the capacity to do or achieve something while adhering to ethical behavior.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Times of Absence Practice</h3>



<p>Practicing Good Ways of Absence can lead to good times, such as a sense of inner peace and satisfaction.</p>



<p>Investigating and understanding the concept of Good Ways of Absence can lead to moments of clarity and enlightenment. It can also lead to a deeper understanding of oneself and others.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Life of Absence Mimesis</h3>



<p>Living a life of Good Ways of Absence can lead to a good life, as it fosters ethical behavior and positive relationships. It can also inspire others to live a similar life.</p>



<p>Inheriting the principles of Good Ways of Absence can lead to a legacy of ethical behavior and positive relationships. It can also inspire future generations to continue the tradition of living a life of Good Ways of Absence.</p>



<p></p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/ethical-absence/">6. Ethical Absence</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7. Mutual Defense</title>
		<link>/mutual-defense/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 12:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=2573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Mutual defense is considered a good way to protect oneself and others because it involves working together and sharing resources to ensure the safety and well-being of all.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/mutual-defense/">7. Mutual Defense</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Crisis Resolutions Training -  Ep06 - Defense" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_daf4LwIIas?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><strong>Crisis Resolutions Video Training &#8211; Episode 6</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Episode 6 Narrative</h2>



<p>Episode 6 focuses on Good Defense as a Mutual Good Way. Defense is a family of Mutual Good Ways that help us protect ourselves and others by being flexible, sensible, sustainable, accessible, and capable.</p>



<p>Mutual defense is considered a good way to protect oneself and others because it involves working together and sharing resources to ensure the safety and well-being of all. This approach allows for greater flexibility and adaptability in the face of crisis, as well as more effective use of resources. Additionally, mutual defense can help build stronger relationships and a sense of community among those involved.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Ways of Defense Genesis</h3>



<p>Defense is a Mutual Good Way that helps us practice our flexibility of Character, Intelligence, Services, Community, and Systems. Our Mutual Flexibility, a quality also shared by our Ears, is the first Defense of our Character. Our Intelligence is a bit chaotic as our Hair. Our Services have a passive and active state as our Mouth. Our Community shares observations like our Eyes do, and our Systems in general are recursive as our breath, filtering information as a Defense mechanism.</p>



<p>Defense means finding ways to protect yourself and others by using common sense in the areas of Management, Curation, Interaction, Cooperation, and Operation. It means working together through our mutual capability of teaching, researching, deploying, designing, and having a shared philosophy.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Times of Defense Practice</h3>



<p>Good Times of Defense Practice can come as a result of taking measures to protect our mental and physical health, implementing safety measures to protect employees from workplace hazards, working together to create a safe and supportive environment for all family members, and promoting policies and practices that protect the well-being of all members of society.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Good Life of Defense Mimesis</h3>



<p>Good Life of Defense Mimesis means incorporating the principles of Good Defense into our lives in a way that is authentic and natural. By living our lives in such a way that we are always mindful of the potential for crisis, and by taking steps to protect ourselves and others, we can create a better world for everyone.</p>



<p>By teaching our children and grandchildren the importance of protecting themselves and others, and by showing them how to do so in a way that is both effective and sustainable, we can ensure that the world will be a safer and more secure place for generations to come.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/mutual-defense/">7. Mutual Defense</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
