<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" >

<channel>
	<title>Crisis Resolutions</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/plus-stream/audio/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Ai Enhanced Good Governance Gamification</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 21:19:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<itunes:subtitle>Crisis Resolutions</itunes:subtitle>
	<itunes:summary>Ai Enhanced Good Governance Gamification</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
	<item>
		<title>S01E05 Flexibility of Systems</title>
		<link>/s01e05-flexibility-of-systems/</link>
					<comments>/s01e05-flexibility-of-systems/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 09:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">.com/?p=2795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to navigate and influence different systems (such as organizational structures, policies or norms) that affect our lives.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e05-flexibility-of-systems/">S01E05 Flexibility of Systems</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How to navigate and influence different systems (such as organizational structures, policies or norms) that affect our lives.</p>
</blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-spotify wp-block-embed-spotify wp-embed-aspect-21-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Spotify Embed: Flexibility of Systems" style="border-radius: 12px" width="100%" height="152" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/5Rqi5MDMYeZeZe5LlmWOGR?si=2ef0262a0897494d&#038;utm_source=oembed"></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Crisis Resolutions <strong>Podcast</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Narrative</strong></h2>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p>Welcome to Crisis Resolutions, a podcast where we explore how to deal with life&#8217;s challenges through good practices and without prejudice. I&#8217;m your host, and in today&#8217;s episode, we&#8217;ll be discussing the flexibility of systems.</p>



<p>What do we mean by systems? Systems are the structures, policies, or norms that shape our lives. They can be formal or informal, large or small, visible or invisible. For example, a system can be your family, your workplace, your community, your country, or even yourself.</p>



<p>Why do we need to be flexible with systems? Because systems are not static. They change over time and interact with each other. Sometimes they can create conflicts or crises that affect us personally or as a group. For example, a system can be disrupted by a natural disaster, a political upheaval, a technological innovation, or a personal crisis.</p>



<p>How can we navigate and influence the different systems that affect our lives? Here are some tips based on research and experience:</p>



<ul>
<li>Recognize that all systems have biased perceptions. We tend to see our own system as fair and rational, and other systems as unfair and irrational. This can lead to misunderstandings and mistrust. To overcome this bias, we need to try to see the situation from different perspectives. We can do this by asking questions, actively listening, and empathizing with others.</li>



<li>Avoid escalating tensions with threats and provocative moves. When we feel threatened or ignored by another system, we may be tempted to make ultimatums or take drastic actions. This can backfire and make the situation worse. Instead of escalating the conflict, we should try to de-escalate it by finding common ground, expressing our interests rather than our positions, and making concessions when appropriate.</li>



<li>Overcome an &#8220;us versus them&#8221; mentality. When we strongly identify with our own system, we may develop an in-group bias that favors our own group over others. This can create hostility and prejudice toward out-groups. To overcome this mentality, we need to expand our sense of identity and belonging. We can do this by creating cross-system connections, finding shared values, and celebrating diversity.</li>



<li>Separate sacred from pseudo-sacred issues. Sometimes we may face a conflict that involves core values that we consider sacred or non-negotiable. These values are often related to our identity, morality, or spirituality. In these cases, it may be very difficult to compromise or change our views. However, sometimes what we think is sacred may actually be pseudo-sacred, meaning that it is not really essential for us, but rather a way of expressing our emotions or preferences. To separate sacred from pseudo-sacred issues, we need to examine our underlying motivations and assumptions, clarify what is truly important for us, and respect what is truly important for others.</li>



<li>Adapt to changing circumstances. Systems are dynamic and complex. They evolve over time in response to internal and external factors. Sometimes they may undergo sudden or radical changes that require us to adjust quickly. To adapt to changing circumstances, we need to be flexible in our thinking and behavior, embrace uncertainty as an opportunity for learning and innovation, and seek feedback and support.</li>
</ul>



<p>These are some ways in which we can practice flexibility of systems during times of crisis. By doing so, we can not only survive but also thrive in a changing world.</p>



<p>Thank you for listening to Crisis Resolutions.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e05-flexibility-of-systems/">S01E05 Flexibility of Systems</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/s01e05-flexibility-of-systems/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S01E04 Flexibility of Community</title>
		<link>/s01e04-flexibility-of-community/</link>
					<comments>/s01e04-flexibility-of-community/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 09:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">.com/?p=2794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to build and maintain strong relationships with diverse groups of people (such as family, friends, colleagues or neighbors) that can provide us with emotional support, practical help or guidance.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e04-flexibility-of-community/">S01E04 Flexibility of Community</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How to build and maintain strong relationships with diverse groups of people (such as family, friends, colleagues or neighbours) that can provide us with emotional support, practical help or guidance.</p>
</blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-spotify wp-block-embed-spotify wp-embed-aspect-21-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Spotify Embed: Flexibility of Community" style="border-radius: 12px" width="100%" height="152" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/3TJbPIagY3CvtM2QGmKMDO?si=1f3145aec2674e88&#038;utm_source=oembed"></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Crisis Resolutions <strong>Podcast</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Narrative</strong></h2>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p>Welcome to Crisis Resolutions, a podcast where we explore how to deal with life&#8217;s challenges through the practice of good ways and without prejudgements.</p>



<p>What do we mean by flexibility of community? It&#8217;s the ability to build and maintain strong relationships with diverse groups of people (such as family, friends, colleagues or neighbors) that can provide us with emotional support, practical help or guidance. Having a flexible community means being open to different perspectives, cultures and values, and being able to adapt to changing situations and needs.</p>



<p>Why is flexibility of community important? Well, research shows that having a strong social network can improve our mental and physical health, reduce stress and increase happiness. It can also help us cope with crises by providing us with resources, information and emotional support. For example, during the COVID-19 pandemic, many people relied on their communities to stay connected, informed and hopeful.</p>



<p>How can we develop flexibility of community? Here are some tips based on our website <a href="/">crisisresolutions.com</a>:</p>



<ul>
<li>Be proactive. Don&#8217;t wait for others to reach out to you; take the initiative to contact them regularly and show interest in their lives. You can also join groups or organizations that share your interests or values, or volunteer for a cause that you care about.</li>



<li>Be respectful. Recognize that everyone has their own opinions, beliefs and preferences, and avoid judging them based on your own standards. Listen actively and empathetically to what they have to say, and try to understand their point of view. You don&#8217;t have to agree with everything they say or do; you just have to respect their right to be different.</li>



<li>Be supportive. Offer help when you can, and ask for help when you need it. Don&#8217;t be afraid to express your feelings or concerns; your community is there for you. Also, celebrate your achievements and successes together; sharing positive emotions can strengthen your bonds.</li>



<li>Be flexible. Understand that people&#8217;s circumstances and needs may change over time; be ready to adjust your expectations accordingly. Don&#8217;t take things personally if someone cancels plans or doesn&#8217;t reply right away; they may have other priorities or challenges at the moment. Also, be open to meeting new people and expanding your network; diversity can enrich your life.</li>
</ul>



<p>Flexibility of community is not something that happens overnight; it takes time and effort to cultivate it. But it&#8217;s worth it because it can make a huge difference in how we deal with crises and how we enjoy life.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s all for today&#8217;s episode; thank you for listening!</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e04-flexibility-of-community/">S01E04 Flexibility of Community</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/s01e04-flexibility-of-community/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S01E03 Flexibility of Services</title>
		<link>/s01e03-flexibility-of-services/</link>
					<comments>/s01e03-flexibility-of-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 09:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">.com/?p=2793</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to access and utilize various types of services (such as health care, social support, legal aid or financial assistance) that can help us meet our needs and goals.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e03-flexibility-of-services/">S01E03 Flexibility of Services</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How to access and utilize various types of services (such as health care, social support, legal aid or financial assistance) that can help us meet our needs and goals.</p>
</blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-spotify wp-block-embed-spotify wp-embed-aspect-21-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Spotify Embed: Flexibility of Services" style="border-radius: 12px" width="100%" height="152" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/23lnxnWoeSuLlMPmGNFDSn?si=cd2688904b4645f6&#038;utm_source=oembed"></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Crisis Resolutions <strong>Podcast</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Narrative</strong></h2>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p>Welcome to Crisis Resolutions, a podcast where we explore how to cope with life&#8217;s challenges through the practice of good ways and without prejudgements. I&#8217;m your host, and today we&#8217;re going to talk about flexibility of services. How can we access and utilize various types of services that can help us meet our needs and goals?</p>



<p>Flexibility of services means being able to choose from a range of options that suit our situation and preferences. It also means being able to adjust our plans as circumstances change. For example, if we are facing a financial crisis, we might need to seek assistance from different sources such as government benefits, charities, family or friends, or loans. We might also need to revise our budget, cut down on expenses, or look for additional income opportunities.</p>



<p>Flexibility of services is important because it can help us overcome barriers and find solutions that work for us. It can also reduce stress and anxiety by giving us a sense of control and hope. However, flexibility of services is not always easy to achieve. Sometimes we might face challenges such as:</p>



<ul>
<li>Lack of information: We might not know what services are available or how to access them.</li>



<li>Lack of access: We might not be able to reach the services we need due to distance, cost, availability, eligibility criteria, or waiting times.</li>



<li>Lack of quality: We might not be satisfied with the services we receive due to poor standards, unprofessionalism, discrimination, or abuse.</li>



<li>Lack of coordination: We might have difficulty navigating multiple services that are not well integrated or communicated with each other.</li>



<li>Lack of trust: We might have doubts or fears about using certain services due to stigma, privacy concerns, negative experiences, or cultural differences.</li>
</ul>



<p>So how can we overcome these challenges and achieve flexibility of services? Here are some tips that might help:</p>



<ul>
<li>Seek information: Do some research online or offline about the types of services that can help you with your specific problem. You can also ask for referrals from people you trust such as your doctor, therapist, social worker, friend or family member.</li>



<li>Compare options: Evaluate the pros and cons of different services based on your needs and preferences. Consider factors such as cost-effectiveness (how much value you get for your money), convenience (how easy it is to use), compatibility (how well it matches your values and beliefs), and credibility (how reliable it is).</li>



<li>Try new things: Be open-minded and willing to try new or alternative services that you might not have considered before. You might discover something that works better for you than what you expected.</li>



<li>Be flexible: Be ready to adapt your plans if things change or don&#8217;t go as planned. You might need to switch providers if you are unhappy with their service quality; seek additional support if your situation worsens; adjust your expectations if your goals are unrealistic; or accept compromise if there is no perfect solution.</li>



<li>Communicate effectively: Communicate clearly and respectfully with the service providers you use. Express your needs and preferences; ask questions; give feedback; negotiate terms; report problems; and thank them for their help.</li>



<li>Build trust: Build rapport and trust with the service providers you use by being honest; respectful; cooperative; appreciative; and compliant with their policies and procedures.</li>



<li>Advocate for change: If you encounter systemic issues that prevent you or others from accessing or utilizing services effectively, you can speak up and advocate for change. This might involve contacting your elected officials, participating in community organizing, or joining a grassroots movement.</li>
</ul>



<p>Remember that flexibility of services is not just about finding the right service for your needs, but also about creating a system that works for everyone. By being proactive, creative, and collaborative, we can help improve the quality, accessibility, and affordability of services for ourselves and others.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s all for today&#8217;s episode of Crisis Resolutions.</p>



<p>Thank you for listening to this episode of our podcast about resolving crises through good practices and without prejudice. If you enjoyed this episode, we kindly ask you to connect with us at <a href="/">crisisresolutions.com</a> and join our mission to resolve crises in a positive and unbiased way. By being part of our community, you&#8217;ll have access to helpful content on building a positive mindset, fun games to boost your mood, and opportunities to make new friends. We&#8217;d be chuffed to have you on board and make a difference together. Thanks for considering our invitation, and we hope to hear from you soon!</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e03-flexibility-of-services/">S01E03 Flexibility of Services</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/s01e03-flexibility-of-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S01E02 Flexibility of Intelligence</title>
		<link>/s01e02-flexibility-of-intelligence/</link>
					<comments>/s01e02-flexibility-of-intelligence/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 09:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">.com/?p=2792</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to use different types of thinking skills (such as analytical, critical, creative and emotional) that can help us understand complex issues and generate innovative ideas.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e02-flexibility-of-intelligence/">S01E02 Flexibility of Intelligence</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How to use different types of thinking skills (such as analytical, critical, creative and emotional) that can help us understand complex issues and generate innovative ideas.</p>
</blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-spotify wp-block-embed-spotify wp-embed-aspect-21-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Spotify Embed: Flexibility of Intelligence" style="border-radius: 12px" width="100%" height="152" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/1Vn1UKQuy1YqwkiypXYCG0?si=589a401facce47ca&#038;utm_source=oembed"></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Crisis Resolutions <strong>Podcast</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Narrative</strong></h2>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p>Welcome to Crisis Resolutions, a podcast where we explore how to deal with challenging situations through the practice of good ways and without prejudgements. I&#8217;m your host, and today we&#8217;re going to talk about flexibility of intelligence &#8211; how to use different types of thinking skills that can help us understand complex issues and generate innovative ideas.</p>



<p>What do we mean by flexibility of intelligence? Well, it&#8217;s the ability to adapt our thinking style according to the context and the problem we&#8217;re facing. It&#8217;s not about being smart or having a high IQ. It&#8217;s about being able to switch between different modes of thinking, such as analytical, critical, creative, and emotional.</p>



<p>Analytical thinking is the ability to break down a problem into smaller parts, identify patterns and relationships, and use logic and evidence to draw conclusions. Critical thinking is the ability to question assumptions, evaluate arguments, identify biases and inconsistencies, and challenge our own and others&#8217; views. Creative thinking is the ability to generate new ideas, solutions, or perspectives that are original, useful, or valuable. Emotional thinking is the ability to understand our own and others&#8217; feelings, motivations, and values, and use them as a source of information and inspiration.</p>



<p>Why do we need flexibility of intelligence? Because we live in a complex and uncertain world that requires us to deal with different kinds of problems that may not have clear-cut answers or solutions. These problems require us to use different types of thinking skills depending on the situation. Sometimes we need to be analytical and logical; sometimes we need to be critical and skeptical; sometimes we need to be creative and imaginative; sometimes we need to be emotional and empathetic.</p>



<p>So, how can we develop flexibility of intelligence? First, we need to be aware of our preferred thinking style. We all have natural tendencies or preferences for certain types of thinking skills based on our personality, education, or experience. Each style has its strengths and weaknesses. The key is to recognize your own style and how it affects your problem-solving process.</p>



<p>Second, we need to be open-minded. One way to expand our thinking skills is to expose ourselves to different perspectives, opinions, or experiences that challenge our assumptions or beliefs. We can read books or articles that present different viewpoints or arguments than ours, listen to podcasts or watch videos that feature people who have different backgrounds or experiences than ours, talk to people who have different opinions or perspectives than ours, or try new activities or hobbies that stimulate our curiosity or creativity.</p>



<p>Third, we need to be curious. Another way to expand our thinking skills is to ask questions, explore possibilities, and experiment with ideas. We can ask ourselves &#8220;what if&#8221; questions that encourage us to imagine alternative scenarios or outcomes, ask others &#8220;how&#8221; questions that invite them to share their insights or experiences, try out new ideas or solutions in small-scale tests or prototypes, or learn from feedback, mistakes, and failures.</p>



<p>Finally, we need to be flexible. A third way to expand our thinking skills is to adapt our style according to the context and the problem we&#8217;re facing. We can use analytical thinking when we need to analyze data, identify causes, or evaluate options; use critical thinking when we need to challenge assumptions, detect flaws, or make decisions; use creative thinking when we need to generate ideas, find opportunities, or overcome obstacles; or use emotional thinking when we need to understand feelings, motivate actions, or build relationships.</p>



<p>In conclusion, flexibility of intelligence is something that you can improve over time. By practicing these tips regularly, you can develop your ability to use different types of thinking skills that can help you understand complex issues and generate innovative ideas.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s all for today&#8217;s episode of Crisis Resolutions. Thank you for listening, and remember: be flexible, be curious, be open-minded, and be well.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e02-flexibility-of-intelligence/">S01E02 Flexibility of Intelligence</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/s01e02-flexibility-of-intelligence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S01E01 Flexibility of Character</title>
		<link>/flexibility-of-character/</link>
					<comments>/flexibility-of-character/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 09:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">.com/?p=2789</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to develop a positive mindset and attitude that can help us face difficulties with courage and optimism.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/flexibility-of-character/">S01E01 Flexibility of Character</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How to develop a positive mindset and attitude that can help us face difficulties with courage and optimism.</p>
</blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-spotify wp-block-embed-spotify wp-embed-aspect-21-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Spotify Embed: Flexibility of Character" style="border-radius: 12px" width="100%" height="152" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/3IiFRYvQsPb3f77w53KkW1?si=ad18c70f69b544b6&#038;utm_source=oembed"></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Crisis Resolutions <strong>Podcast</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Narrative</strong></h2>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p>Welcome to the first episode of our podcast about crisis resolutions through the practice of good ways and without prejudgements. I&#8217;m your host, and today we&#8217;re going to talk about flexibility of character.</p>



<p>What is flexibility of character? It&#8217;s the ability to adapt to changing circumstances and cope with challenges in a positive and constructive way. It&#8217;s also the willingness to learn from others and appreciate different perspectives. Flexibility of character can help us face difficulties with courage and optimism, instead of being rigid, defensive or pessimistic.</p>



<p>Why is flexibility of character important for crisis resolution? Because crises are unpredictable, complex and stressful situations that require quick and effective responses. Crises can also trigger strong emotions, such as fear, anger or guilt, that can cloud our judgment and impair our communication. If we are flexible in our character, we can manage our emotions better, avoid escalating tensions with threats or provocative moves, overcome an us, versus them mentality and find creative solutions that benefit everyone involved.</p>



<p>How can we develop flexibility of character? Here are some tips based on research and best practices:</p>



<ul>
<li>Identify risks. Good crisis management starts with anticipation of risks that a company may face. By being aware of potential threats and vulnerabilities, we can prepare ourselves mentally and emotionally for dealing with them if they arise.</li>



<li>Define an action plan. Having a clear plan for how to respond to a crisis can reduce uncertainty and anxiety. A good action plan should include roles and responsibilities, communication channels, resources and contingency measures.</li>



<li>Establish a crisis unit. A crisis unit is a team of people who are responsible for handling the crisis. The members of the crisis unit should have relevant skills, experience and authority to make decisions. They should also have trust and respect for each other, as well as a shared vision and goal.</li>



<li>Define messages to transmit. The messages that are transmitted during a crisis should reflect the values and principles of the organization. They should also acknowledge the problem, express empathy for those affected, explain what actions are being taken and what outcomes are expected.</li>



<li>Prepare for crisis management by making time, energy, and attention available. Prioritize tasks based on their urgency and importance, delegate responsibilities whenever possible, and take breaks when necessary.</li>



<li>Maintain a positive attitude during a crisis to cope better with stress and motivate those around us. Focus on what can be controlled, recognize strengths, and celebrate small wins.</li>
</ul>



<p>These are some ways to develop a flexible character that can help us effectively and efficiently resolve crises.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/flexibility-of-character/">S01E01 Flexibility of Character</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/flexibility-of-character/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crisis Resolutions Podcast Trailer</title>
		<link>/crisis-resolutions-podcast-trailer/</link>
					<comments>/crisis-resolutions-podcast-trailer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 08:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">.com/?p=2755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In this podcast series, we will explore how to resolve crises through good ways of mutual defense</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/crisis-resolutions-podcast-trailer/">Crisis Resolutions Podcast Trailer</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-spotify wp-block-embed-spotify wp-embed-aspect-21-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Spotify Embed: Trailer" style="border-radius: 12px" width="100%" height="152" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/3gKRkVFcikuptWossfMDaK?si=41e4aef1bc174fa1&#038;utm_source=oembed"></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Narrative</h2>



<p>Crisis resolution is a vital skill for anyone who faces challenges and difficulties in their personal or professional life. Crises can arise from various sources, such as mental health problems, financial stress, interpersonal conflicts, natural disasters or political instability. Crises can have serious consequences for individuals and communities, such as emotional distress, physical harm, social isolation or economic loss.<br>However, crises can also be opportunities for growth and transformation if they are handled effectively and constructively. One way to achieve this is through good ways of mutual defense, which means supporting oneself and others in times of crisis by using various strategies and resources that can enhance resilience and recovery.</p>



<p>In this podcast series, we will explore how to resolve crises through good ways of mutual defense based on a model that consists of five dimensions: flexibility, sensibility, sustainability, accessibility and capability. Each dimension covers different aspects of crisis resolution that can help us cope with adversity and overcome challenges.<br>The podcast series will consist of 25 episodes, each focusing on one element of each dimension. The episodes will feature insights, practical exercises and tips that listeners can try out themselves or with others.</p>



<p>We&#8217;d be chuffed to have you on board and make a difference together. Please join our mission to resolve crises positively and without bias by connecting with us at <a href="/">crisisresolutions.com</a>.<br>By becoming part of our community, you will have access to helpful content, fun games, and opportunities to make new friends. Thank you for listening. Cheers!</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/crisis-resolutions-podcast-trailer/">Crisis Resolutions Podcast Trailer</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/crisis-resolutions-podcast-trailer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
