<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" >

<channel>
	<title>Crisis Resolutions</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/plus-stream/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Ai Enhanced Good Governance Gamification</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 21:00:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<itunes:subtitle>Crisis Resolutions</itunes:subtitle>
	<itunes:summary>Ai Enhanced Good Governance Gamification</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
	<item>
		<title>S01E02 Flexibility of Intelligence</title>
		<link>/s01e02-flexibility-of-intelligence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 09:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=2792</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to use different types of thinking skills (such as analytical, critical, creative and emotional) that can help us understand complex issues and generate innovative ideas.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e02-flexibility-of-intelligence/">S01E02 Flexibility of Intelligence</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How to use different types of thinking skills (such as analytical, critical, creative and emotional) that can help us understand complex issues and generate innovative ideas.</p>
</blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-spotify wp-block-embed-spotify wp-embed-aspect-21-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Spotify Embed: Flexibility of Intelligence" style="border-radius: 12px" width="100%" height="152" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/1Vn1UKQuy1YqwkiypXYCG0?si=589a401facce47ca&#038;utm_source=oembed"></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Crisis Resolutions <strong>Podcast</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Narrative</strong></h2>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p>Welcome to Crisis Resolutions, a podcast where we explore how to deal with challenging situations through the practice of good ways and without prejudgements. I&#8217;m your host, and today we&#8217;re going to talk about flexibility of intelligence &#8211; how to use different types of thinking skills that can help us understand complex issues and generate innovative ideas.</p>



<p>What do we mean by flexibility of intelligence? Well, it&#8217;s the ability to adapt our thinking style according to the context and the problem we&#8217;re facing. It&#8217;s not about being smart or having a high IQ. It&#8217;s about being able to switch between different modes of thinking, such as analytical, critical, creative, and emotional.</p>



<p>Analytical thinking is the ability to break down a problem into smaller parts, identify patterns and relationships, and use logic and evidence to draw conclusions. Critical thinking is the ability to question assumptions, evaluate arguments, identify biases and inconsistencies, and challenge our own and others&#8217; views. Creative thinking is the ability to generate new ideas, solutions, or perspectives that are original, useful, or valuable. Emotional thinking is the ability to understand our own and others&#8217; feelings, motivations, and values, and use them as a source of information and inspiration.</p>



<p>Why do we need flexibility of intelligence? Because we live in a complex and uncertain world that requires us to deal with different kinds of problems that may not have clear-cut answers or solutions. These problems require us to use different types of thinking skills depending on the situation. Sometimes we need to be analytical and logical; sometimes we need to be critical and skeptical; sometimes we need to be creative and imaginative; sometimes we need to be emotional and empathetic.</p>



<p>So, how can we develop flexibility of intelligence? First, we need to be aware of our preferred thinking style. We all have natural tendencies or preferences for certain types of thinking skills based on our personality, education, or experience. Each style has its strengths and weaknesses. The key is to recognize your own style and how it affects your problem-solving process.</p>



<p>Second, we need to be open-minded. One way to expand our thinking skills is to expose ourselves to different perspectives, opinions, or experiences that challenge our assumptions or beliefs. We can read books or articles that present different viewpoints or arguments than ours, listen to podcasts or watch videos that feature people who have different backgrounds or experiences than ours, talk to people who have different opinions or perspectives than ours, or try new activities or hobbies that stimulate our curiosity or creativity.</p>



<p>Third, we need to be curious. Another way to expand our thinking skills is to ask questions, explore possibilities, and experiment with ideas. We can ask ourselves &#8220;what if&#8221; questions that encourage us to imagine alternative scenarios or outcomes, ask others &#8220;how&#8221; questions that invite them to share their insights or experiences, try out new ideas or solutions in small-scale tests or prototypes, or learn from feedback, mistakes, and failures.</p>



<p>Finally, we need to be flexible. A third way to expand our thinking skills is to adapt our style according to the context and the problem we&#8217;re facing. We can use analytical thinking when we need to analyze data, identify causes, or evaluate options; use critical thinking when we need to challenge assumptions, detect flaws, or make decisions; use creative thinking when we need to generate ideas, find opportunities, or overcome obstacles; or use emotional thinking when we need to understand feelings, motivate actions, or build relationships.</p>



<p>In conclusion, flexibility of intelligence is something that you can improve over time. By practicing these tips regularly, you can develop your ability to use different types of thinking skills that can help you understand complex issues and generate innovative ideas.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s all for today&#8217;s episode of Crisis Resolutions. Thank you for listening, and remember: be flexible, be curious, be open-minded, and be well.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e02-flexibility-of-intelligence/">S01E02 Flexibility of Intelligence</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S01E03 Flexibility of Services</title>
		<link>/s01e03-flexibility-of-services/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 09:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=2793</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to access and utilize various types of services (such as health care, social support, legal aid or financial assistance) that can help us meet our needs and goals.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e03-flexibility-of-services/">S01E03 Flexibility of Services</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How to access and utilize various types of services (such as health care, social support, legal aid or financial assistance) that can help us meet our needs and goals.</p>
</blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-spotify wp-block-embed-spotify wp-embed-aspect-21-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Spotify Embed: Flexibility of Services" style="border-radius: 12px" width="100%" height="152" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/23lnxnWoeSuLlMPmGNFDSn?si=cd2688904b4645f6&#038;utm_source=oembed"></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Crisis Resolutions <strong>Podcast</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Narrative</strong></h2>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p>Welcome to Crisis Resolutions, a podcast where we explore how to cope with life&#8217;s challenges through the practice of good ways and without prejudgements. I&#8217;m your host, and today we&#8217;re going to talk about flexibility of services. How can we access and utilize various types of services that can help us meet our needs and goals?</p>



<p>Flexibility of services means being able to choose from a range of options that suit our situation and preferences. It also means being able to adjust our plans as circumstances change. For example, if we are facing a financial crisis, we might need to seek assistance from different sources such as government benefits, charities, family or friends, or loans. We might also need to revise our budget, cut down on expenses, or look for additional income opportunities.</p>



<p>Flexibility of services is important because it can help us overcome barriers and find solutions that work for us. It can also reduce stress and anxiety by giving us a sense of control and hope. However, flexibility of services is not always easy to achieve. Sometimes we might face challenges such as:</p>



<ul>
<li>Lack of information: We might not know what services are available or how to access them.</li>



<li>Lack of access: We might not be able to reach the services we need due to distance, cost, availability, eligibility criteria, or waiting times.</li>



<li>Lack of quality: We might not be satisfied with the services we receive due to poor standards, unprofessionalism, discrimination, or abuse.</li>



<li>Lack of coordination: We might have difficulty navigating multiple services that are not well integrated or communicated with each other.</li>



<li>Lack of trust: We might have doubts or fears about using certain services due to stigma, privacy concerns, negative experiences, or cultural differences.</li>
</ul>



<p>So how can we overcome these challenges and achieve flexibility of services? Here are some tips that might help:</p>



<ul>
<li>Seek information: Do some research online or offline about the types of services that can help you with your specific problem. You can also ask for referrals from people you trust such as your doctor, therapist, social worker, friend or family member.</li>



<li>Compare options: Evaluate the pros and cons of different services based on your needs and preferences. Consider factors such as cost-effectiveness (how much value you get for your money), convenience (how easy it is to use), compatibility (how well it matches your values and beliefs), and credibility (how reliable it is).</li>



<li>Try new things: Be open-minded and willing to try new or alternative services that you might not have considered before. You might discover something that works better for you than what you expected.</li>



<li>Be flexible: Be ready to adapt your plans if things change or don&#8217;t go as planned. You might need to switch providers if you are unhappy with their service quality; seek additional support if your situation worsens; adjust your expectations if your goals are unrealistic; or accept compromise if there is no perfect solution.</li>



<li>Communicate effectively: Communicate clearly and respectfully with the service providers you use. Express your needs and preferences; ask questions; give feedback; negotiate terms; report problems; and thank them for their help.</li>



<li>Build trust: Build rapport and trust with the service providers you use by being honest; respectful; cooperative; appreciative; and compliant with their policies and procedures.</li>



<li>Advocate for change: If you encounter systemic issues that prevent you or others from accessing or utilizing services effectively, you can speak up and advocate for change. This might involve contacting your elected officials, participating in community organizing, or joining a grassroots movement.</li>
</ul>



<p>Remember that flexibility of services is not just about finding the right service for your needs, but also about creating a system that works for everyone. By being proactive, creative, and collaborative, we can help improve the quality, accessibility, and affordability of services for ourselves and others.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s all for today&#8217;s episode of Crisis Resolutions.</p>



<p>Thank you for listening to this episode of our podcast about resolving crises through good practices and without prejudice. If you enjoyed this episode, we kindly ask you to connect with us at <a href="/">crisisresolutions.com</a> and join our mission to resolve crises in a positive and unbiased way. By being part of our community, you&#8217;ll have access to helpful content on building a positive mindset, fun games to boost your mood, and opportunities to make new friends. We&#8217;d be chuffed to have you on board and make a difference together. Thanks for considering our invitation, and we hope to hear from you soon!</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e03-flexibility-of-services/">S01E03 Flexibility of Services</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S01E04 Flexibility of Community</title>
		<link>/s01e04-flexibility-of-community/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 09:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=2794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to build and maintain strong relationships with diverse groups of people (such as family, friends, colleagues or neighbors) that can provide us with emotional support, practical help or guidance.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e04-flexibility-of-community/">S01E04 Flexibility of Community</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How to build and maintain strong relationships with diverse groups of people (such as family, friends, colleagues or neighbours) that can provide us with emotional support, practical help or guidance.</p>
</blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-spotify wp-block-embed-spotify wp-embed-aspect-21-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Spotify Embed: Flexibility of Community" style="border-radius: 12px" width="100%" height="152" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/3TJbPIagY3CvtM2QGmKMDO?si=1f3145aec2674e88&#038;utm_source=oembed"></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Crisis Resolutions <strong>Podcast</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Narrative</strong></h2>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p>Welcome to Crisis Resolutions, a podcast where we explore how to deal with life&#8217;s challenges through the practice of good ways and without prejudgements.</p>



<p>What do we mean by flexibility of community? It&#8217;s the ability to build and maintain strong relationships with diverse groups of people (such as family, friends, colleagues or neighbors) that can provide us with emotional support, practical help or guidance. Having a flexible community means being open to different perspectives, cultures and values, and being able to adapt to changing situations and needs.</p>



<p>Why is flexibility of community important? Well, research shows that having a strong social network can improve our mental and physical health, reduce stress and increase happiness. It can also help us cope with crises by providing us with resources, information and emotional support. For example, during the COVID-19 pandemic, many people relied on their communities to stay connected, informed and hopeful.</p>



<p>How can we develop flexibility of community? Here are some tips based on our website <a href="/">crisisresolutions.com</a>:</p>



<ul>
<li>Be proactive. Don&#8217;t wait for others to reach out to you; take the initiative to contact them regularly and show interest in their lives. You can also join groups or organizations that share your interests or values, or volunteer for a cause that you care about.</li>



<li>Be respectful. Recognize that everyone has their own opinions, beliefs and preferences, and avoid judging them based on your own standards. Listen actively and empathetically to what they have to say, and try to understand their point of view. You don&#8217;t have to agree with everything they say or do; you just have to respect their right to be different.</li>



<li>Be supportive. Offer help when you can, and ask for help when you need it. Don&#8217;t be afraid to express your feelings or concerns; your community is there for you. Also, celebrate your achievements and successes together; sharing positive emotions can strengthen your bonds.</li>



<li>Be flexible. Understand that people&#8217;s circumstances and needs may change over time; be ready to adjust your expectations accordingly. Don&#8217;t take things personally if someone cancels plans or doesn&#8217;t reply right away; they may have other priorities or challenges at the moment. Also, be open to meeting new people and expanding your network; diversity can enrich your life.</li>
</ul>



<p>Flexibility of community is not something that happens overnight; it takes time and effort to cultivate it. But it&#8217;s worth it because it can make a huge difference in how we deal with crises and how we enjoy life.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s all for today&#8217;s episode; thank you for listening!</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e04-flexibility-of-community/">S01E04 Flexibility of Community</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S01E05 Flexibility of Systems</title>
		<link>/s01e05-flexibility-of-systems/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 09:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Audio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=2795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to navigate and influence different systems (such as organizational structures, policies or norms) that affect our lives.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e05-flexibility-of-systems/">S01E05 Flexibility of Systems</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>How to navigate and influence different systems (such as organizational structures, policies or norms) that affect our lives.</p>
</blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-spotify wp-block-embed-spotify wp-embed-aspect-21-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Spotify Embed: Flexibility of Systems" style="border-radius: 12px" width="100%" height="152" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/5Rqi5MDMYeZeZe5LlmWOGR?si=2ef0262a0897494d&#038;utm_source=oembed"></iframe>
</div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Crisis Resolutions <strong>Podcast</strong></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Narrative</strong></h2>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p>Welcome to Crisis Resolutions, a podcast where we explore how to deal with life&#8217;s challenges through good practices and without prejudice. I&#8217;m your host, and in today&#8217;s episode, we&#8217;ll be discussing the flexibility of systems.</p>



<p>What do we mean by systems? Systems are the structures, policies, or norms that shape our lives. They can be formal or informal, large or small, visible or invisible. For example, a system can be your family, your workplace, your community, your country, or even yourself.</p>



<p>Why do we need to be flexible with systems? Because systems are not static. They change over time and interact with each other. Sometimes they can create conflicts or crises that affect us personally or as a group. For example, a system can be disrupted by a natural disaster, a political upheaval, a technological innovation, or a personal crisis.</p>



<p>How can we navigate and influence the different systems that affect our lives? Here are some tips based on research and experience:</p>



<ul>
<li>Recognize that all systems have biased perceptions. We tend to see our own system as fair and rational, and other systems as unfair and irrational. This can lead to misunderstandings and mistrust. To overcome this bias, we need to try to see the situation from different perspectives. We can do this by asking questions, actively listening, and empathizing with others.</li>



<li>Avoid escalating tensions with threats and provocative moves. When we feel threatened or ignored by another system, we may be tempted to make ultimatums or take drastic actions. This can backfire and make the situation worse. Instead of escalating the conflict, we should try to de-escalate it by finding common ground, expressing our interests rather than our positions, and making concessions when appropriate.</li>



<li>Overcome an &#8220;us versus them&#8221; mentality. When we strongly identify with our own system, we may develop an in-group bias that favors our own group over others. This can create hostility and prejudice toward out-groups. To overcome this mentality, we need to expand our sense of identity and belonging. We can do this by creating cross-system connections, finding shared values, and celebrating diversity.</li>



<li>Separate sacred from pseudo-sacred issues. Sometimes we may face a conflict that involves core values that we consider sacred or non-negotiable. These values are often related to our identity, morality, or spirituality. In these cases, it may be very difficult to compromise or change our views. However, sometimes what we think is sacred may actually be pseudo-sacred, meaning that it is not really essential for us, but rather a way of expressing our emotions or preferences. To separate sacred from pseudo-sacred issues, we need to examine our underlying motivations and assumptions, clarify what is truly important for us, and respect what is truly important for others.</li>



<li>Adapt to changing circumstances. Systems are dynamic and complex. They evolve over time in response to internal and external factors. Sometimes they may undergo sudden or radical changes that require us to adjust quickly. To adapt to changing circumstances, we need to be flexible in our thinking and behavior, embrace uncertainty as an opportunity for learning and innovation, and seek feedback and support.</li>
</ul>



<p>These are some ways in which we can practice flexibility of systems during times of crisis. By doing so, we can not only survive but also thrive in a changing world.</p>



<p>Thank you for listening to Crisis Resolutions.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/s01e05-flexibility-of-systems/">S01E05 Flexibility of Systems</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>1. About Crisis Resolution Docs+</title>
		<link>/crisis-resolutions-docs-plus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 18:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Docs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=3303</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Crisis Resolutions Docs Plus (For Friends &#038; Family) is a documentation that provides training guidelines for personal crisis management, as well as tips for general well-being.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/crisis-resolutions-docs-plus/">1. About Crisis Resolution Docs+</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="3303" class="elementor elementor-3303" data-elementor-post-type="post">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4d753cc e-flex e-con-boxed e-con e-parent" data-id="4d753cc" data-element_type="container" data-core-v316-plus="true">
					<div class="e-con-inner">
		<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-77262ae e-con-full e-flex e-con e-child" data-id="77262ae" data-element_type="container">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-59b124c elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="59b124c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<style>/*! elementor - v3.20.0 - 26-03-2024 */
.elementor-widget-text-editor.elementor-drop-cap-view-stacked .elementor-drop-cap{background-color:#69727d;color:#fff}.elementor-widget-text-editor.elementor-drop-cap-view-framed .elementor-drop-cap{color:#69727d;border:3px solid;background-color:transparent}.elementor-widget-text-editor:not(.elementor-drop-cap-view-default) .elementor-drop-cap{margin-top:8px}.elementor-widget-text-editor:not(.elementor-drop-cap-view-default) .elementor-drop-cap-letter{width:1em;height:1em}.elementor-widget-text-editor .elementor-drop-cap{float:left;text-align:center;line-height:1;font-size:50px}.elementor-widget-text-editor .elementor-drop-cap-letter{display:inline-block}</style>				<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Crisis Resolutions Docs Plus (For Friends &amp; Family) is a documentation that provides training guidelines for personal crisis management, as well as tips for general well-being.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-f327059 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="f327059" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<style>/*! elementor - v3.20.0 - 26-03-2024 */
.elementor-widget-divider{--divider-border-style:none;--divider-border-width:1px;--divider-color:#0c0d0e;--divider-icon-size:20px;--divider-element-spacing:10px;--divider-pattern-height:24px;--divider-pattern-size:20px;--divider-pattern-url:none;--divider-pattern-repeat:repeat-x}.elementor-widget-divider .elementor-divider{display:flex}.elementor-widget-divider .elementor-divider__text{font-size:15px;line-height:1;max-width:95%}.elementor-widget-divider .elementor-divider__element{margin:0 var(--divider-element-spacing);flex-shrink:0}.elementor-widget-divider .elementor-icon{font-size:var(--divider-icon-size)}.elementor-widget-divider .elementor-divider-separator{display:flex;margin:0;direction:ltr}.elementor-widget-divider--view-line_icon .elementor-divider-separator,.elementor-widget-divider--view-line_text .elementor-divider-separator{align-items:center}.elementor-widget-divider--view-line_icon .elementor-divider-separator:after,.elementor-widget-divider--view-line_icon .elementor-divider-separator:before,.elementor-widget-divider--view-line_text .elementor-divider-separator:after,.elementor-widget-divider--view-line_text .elementor-divider-separator:before{display:block;content:"";border-block-end:0;flex-grow:1;border-block-start:var(--divider-border-width) var(--divider-border-style) var(--divider-color)}.elementor-widget-divider--element-align-left .elementor-divider .elementor-divider-separator>.elementor-divider__svg:first-of-type{flex-grow:0;flex-shrink:100}.elementor-widget-divider--element-align-left .elementor-divider-separator:before{content:none}.elementor-widget-divider--element-align-left .elementor-divider__element{margin-left:0}.elementor-widget-divider--element-align-right .elementor-divider .elementor-divider-separator>.elementor-divider__svg:last-of-type{flex-grow:0;flex-shrink:100}.elementor-widget-divider--element-align-right .elementor-divider-separator:after{content:none}.elementor-widget-divider--element-align-right .elementor-divider__element{margin-right:0}.elementor-widget-divider--element-align-start .elementor-divider .elementor-divider-separator>.elementor-divider__svg:first-of-type{flex-grow:0;flex-shrink:100}.elementor-widget-divider--element-align-start .elementor-divider-separator:before{content:none}.elementor-widget-divider--element-align-start .elementor-divider__element{margin-inline-start:0}.elementor-widget-divider--element-align-end .elementor-divider .elementor-divider-separator>.elementor-divider__svg:last-of-type{flex-grow:0;flex-shrink:100}.elementor-widget-divider--element-align-end .elementor-divider-separator:after{content:none}.elementor-widget-divider--element-align-end .elementor-divider__element{margin-inline-end:0}.elementor-widget-divider:not(.elementor-widget-divider--view-line_text):not(.elementor-widget-divider--view-line_icon) .elementor-divider-separator{border-block-start:var(--divider-border-width) var(--divider-border-style) var(--divider-color)}.elementor-widget-divider--separator-type-pattern{--divider-border-style:none}.elementor-widget-divider--separator-type-pattern.elementor-widget-divider--view-line .elementor-divider-separator,.elementor-widget-divider--separator-type-pattern:not(.elementor-widget-divider--view-line) .elementor-divider-separator:after,.elementor-widget-divider--separator-type-pattern:not(.elementor-widget-divider--view-line) .elementor-divider-separator:before,.elementor-widget-divider--separator-type-pattern:not([class*=elementor-widget-divider--view]) .elementor-divider-separator{width:100%;min-height:var(--divider-pattern-height);-webkit-mask-size:var(--divider-pattern-size) 100%;mask-size:var(--divider-pattern-size) 100%;-webkit-mask-repeat:var(--divider-pattern-repeat);mask-repeat:var(--divider-pattern-repeat);background-color:var(--divider-color);-webkit-mask-image:var(--divider-pattern-url);mask-image:var(--divider-pattern-url)}.elementor-widget-divider--no-spacing{--divider-pattern-size:auto}.elementor-widget-divider--bg-round{--divider-pattern-repeat:round}.rtl .elementor-widget-divider .elementor-divider__text{direction:rtl}.e-con-inner>.elementor-widget-divider,.e-con>.elementor-widget-divider{width:var(--container-widget-width,100%);--flex-grow:var(--container-widget-flex-grow)}</style>		<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3e1e439 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3e1e439" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><span style="text-align: var(--text-align); font-family: var( --e-global-typography-text-font-family ), Sans-serif; font-size: var( --e-global-typography-text-font-size ); font-style: var( --e-global-typography-text-font-style ); font-weight: var( --e-global-typography-text-font-weight );">Each Chapter includes a set of principles that provide a framework for personal growth and development. These principles are based on years of research and studies by experts in the field of psychology and self-help. Readers can be assured that the methods presented are backed by scientific evidence and have been proven to be effective in improving one&#8217;s life.</span><br></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Furthermore, in addition to the principles, each chapter also includes tips and scientific studies that readers can examine and apply to their daily lives. These tips are designed to help readers internalize and apply the principles in a meaningful way, so that they can experience real change and growth.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Moreover, the benefits of implementing these principles are not limited to personal growth and development. By applying them to their professional lives, individuals can also improve their performance and productivity. They can become more effective leaders, better communicators, and more successful in their careers.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph {"placeholder":"Type / to choose a block, or press space to summon the AI Copilot"} --></p>
<p>Ultimately, by following these guidelines, individuals can create a better future not only for themselves, but also for those around them. They can contribute to a more positive and thriving community, and make a lasting impact on the world.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-edb3756 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="edb3756" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-92f5c98 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="92f5c98" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<style>/*! elementor - v3.20.0 - 26-03-2024 */
.elementor-heading-title{padding:0;margin:0;line-height:1}.elementor-widget-heading .elementor-heading-title[class*=elementor-size-]>a{color:inherit;font-size:inherit;line-height:inherit}.elementor-widget-heading .elementor-heading-title.elementor-size-small{font-size:15px}.elementor-widget-heading .elementor-heading-title.elementor-size-medium{font-size:19px}.elementor-widget-heading .elementor-heading-title.elementor-size-large{font-size:29px}.elementor-widget-heading .elementor-heading-title.elementor-size-xl{font-size:39px}.elementor-widget-heading .elementor-heading-title.elementor-size-xxl{font-size:59px}</style><h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What’s the matter?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c09b215 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="c09b215" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>To handle crises, we can develop good practices through training. This framework helps us improve our personal flexibility, emotional intelligence, decision-making skills, relationships, and ethical responsibility.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Here are some ways to develop these skills:</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>#GoodFlexibility: Being adaptable to changes and open to new experiences.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>#GoodSensibility: Having a healthy mindset and understanding our emotions.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>#GoodSustainability: Making sustainable decisions.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>#GoodAccessibility: Having supportive relationships and a support system.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>#GoodCapability: Making ethical decisions and being responsible for our actions.</li>
</ul>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6b645af elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="6b645af" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-9d3d945 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="9d3d945" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What Experts say?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-2474707 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="2474707" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>According to a study conducted by Kumpfer and Alvarado (2003), individuals who demonstrate personal flexibility, including a positive attitude, are more capable of effectively handling crises.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>In addition, a study by Lamond and Daniels (2016) revealed that individuals with high levels of mental sensibility, such as self-awareness and emotional intelligence, are more resilient to stress and better able to handle crises.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Lastly, a study by Linnenbrink-Garcia and Pekrun (2011) found that individuals with a strong sense of ethical capability, including a solid moral compass, are better equipped to handle crises that challenge their values.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4b059d5 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="4b059d5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c7062ce elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="c7062ce" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">Why we do it?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-25c0f2f elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="25c0f2f" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Let’s explore now together, five essential aspects that can help us resolve crises and overcome difficult situations. Each of these aspects represents a Good Life Quest that can help us maintain our well-being in times of crisis.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:list {"ordered":true} --></p>
<ol><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>The first aspect is #GoodFlexibility, which involves being adaptable and open to change. As Heraclitus, a Greek philosopher, once said, &#8220;The only constant in life is change.&#8221; Life is unpredictable, and we may face unexpected situations that require us to take a different approach. Therefore, it is essential to be flexible and open-minded to new solutions and ideas. We should be willing to learn and adapt to our changing circumstances.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>The second aspect is #GoodSensibility, which involves taking care of our mental health. As Sigmund Freud, an Austrian neurologist and founder of psychoanalysis, famously said, &#8220;The mind is like an iceberg; it floats with one-seventh of its bulk above water.&#8221; Mental health is crucial to our overall well-being, and it is essential to prioritize it during a crisis. We must be aware of our emotions and thoughts and seek help when needed. It&#8217;s important to take breaks and practice self-care, such as meditation, exercise, and sleeping well.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>The third aspect is #GoodSustainability, which involves creating a stable and sustainable environment for financial growth. As Suze Orman, an American financial advisor, once said, &#8220;A big part of financial freedom is having your heart and mind free from worry about the what-ifs of life.&#8221; We must create a budget, save money, and plan for the future. This can help us be prepared for unexpected expenses and reduce our stress levels.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>The fourth aspect is #GoodAccessibility, which involves creating a supportive environment. As Maya Angelou, an American poet and civil rights activist, once said, &#8220;I&#8217;ve learned that people will forget what you said, people will forget what you did, but people will never forget how you made them feel.&#8221; We must surround ourselves with people who care about our well-being and who we can rely on during challenging times. We should communicate our feelings and problems with our friends and family and seek their support.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>The fifth and final aspect is #GoodCapability, which involves promoting ethical values and practices. As Mahatma Gandhi, an Indian independence activist, once said, &#8220;The difference between what we do and what we are capable of doing would suffice to solve most of the world&#8217;s problems.&#8221; During a crisis, we must be responsible for our actions and consider their impact on others. We should strive to do the right thing, even if it is difficult.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --></ol>
<p><!-- /wp:list --><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Remember, these aspects are not just for handling crises; they can help us maintain our well-being and lead a fulfilling life. By being flexible, taking care of our mental health, being financially stable, surrounded by supportive people, and promoting ethical values, we can lead a happier and more fulfilling life.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-ce76d65 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="ce76d65" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-558a552 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="558a552" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">How to do it</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3fba3da elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3fba3da" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Our Crisis Resolutions Training is a comprehensive, self-paced program designed to equip individuals with the necessary tools and skills to manage crises effectively. We cater to individuals from all walks of life, offering free resources for everyone, as well as premium content for those who wish to practice more seriously. Our business-oriented materials are tailor-made for crisis resolution-oriented entrepreneurs, providing them with the knowledge and expertise to navigate difficult situations that arise in the workplace.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>At Crisis Resolutions, we understand that everyone learns differently, which is why we offer a range of learning materials, including guides, video courses, podcasts, and more. Our Training revolves around our Good Ways Model and our Games, which are platforms for personal, social, and professional practice. We believe that practice makes perfect, which is why we provide step-by-step examples of practices in every chapter, as well as tips from experts.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6967c00 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="6967c00" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6a5bcb4 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="6a5bcb4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What to do</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-d251198 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="d251198" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>There are many ways to effectively practice crisis resolution. Our Training provides a routine that can be tailored to fit our personal needs and preferences. We can shape our training in the way that seems most sensible to us.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>We approach Good Ways as a Cooperative Game we can be good at, and Play together as if we were playing music.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To Resonate on Good Vibes, here are some tasks for personal crisis resolution based on scientific journals, studies, and other authoritative resources.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><strong>Here are the top 10 Tasks for personal crisis resolution:</strong></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:list {"ordered":true} --></p>
<ol><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>Focus on the present moment and avoid dwelling on the past or worrying about the future. This can help reduce stress and anxiety.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>Practice self-care activities such as meditation, exercise, and getting enough sleep.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>Seek support from friends, family, or a mental health professional. Talking to someone about your feelings and problems can help alleviate stress and anxiety.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>Create a budget and plan for the future to reduce financial stress.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>Be open-minded and flexible when faced with unexpected situations or challenges.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>Practice self-compassion and avoid negative self-talk.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>Set realistic goals and prioritize tasks to help manage stress.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>Identify and avoid things that may make stress or anxiety worse.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>Promote ethical values and practices by being responsible for your actions and considering their impact on others.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>Focus on personal growth and learning from the crisis experience.</li>
</ol>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-02aa08d elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="02aa08d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6b709f5 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="6b709f5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h4 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">References</h4>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3c3b0d9 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3c3b0d9" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<!-- /wp:quote --><!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p> </p>
<!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:list -->
<ul><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>Kumpfer, K. L., &amp; Alvarado, R. (2003). <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2003-09215-001" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Family-strengthening approaches for the prevention of youth problem behaviors</a>. American Psychologist, 58(6-7), 457-465.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>Lamond, E., &amp; Daniels, K. (2016). <a href="https://www.emerald.com/insight/content/doi/10.1108/JMP-07-2014-0197/full/html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">The relationship between emotional intelligence and stress: A review</a>. Journal of Managerial Psychology, 31(2), 327-342.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --><!-- wp:list-item -->
<li>Linnenbrink-Garcia, L., &amp; Pekrun, R. (2011). <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0361476X1000086X" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Students&#8217; emotions and academic engagement: Introduction to the special issue</a>. Contemporary Educational Psychology, 36(1), 1-3.</li>
<!-- /wp:list-item --></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->						</div>
				</div>
				</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				</div>
		<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/crisis-resolutions-docs-plus/">1. About Crisis Resolution Docs+</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2. Good Ways</title>
		<link>/2-good-ways/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 20:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Docs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=3330</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The main idea of our model is that General Well-being is important, and there are 8 Main Good Ways you can practice to achieve this.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2-good-ways/">2. Good Ways</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="3330" class="elementor elementor-3330" data-elementor-post-type="post">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4d753cc e-flex e-con-boxed e-con e-parent" data-id="4d753cc" data-element_type="container" data-core-v316-plus="true">
					<div class="e-con-inner">
		<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-77262ae e-con-full e-flex e-con e-child" data-id="77262ae" data-element_type="container">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-59b124c elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="59b124c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Crisis Resolutions Docs Plus (For Friends &amp; Family) is a documentation that provides training guidelines for personal crisis management, as well as tips for general well-being.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-edb3756 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="edb3756" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-92f5c98 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="92f5c98" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What’s the matter?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c09b215 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="c09b215" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>The main idea of our model is that General Well-being is important, and there are 8 Main Good Ways you can practice to achieve this. These are:</p>
<ol>
<li>Personal Continence, which involves taking care of oneself physically and emotionally.</li>
<li>Mental Conscience, which involves being aware of one’s actions and making choices that align with one’s values.</li>
<li>Practical Presence, which involves being present in the moment and focusing on what is important.</li>
<li>Social Sense, which involves being aware of others’ needs and feelings.</li>
<li>Ethical Absence, which involves avoiding unethical behavior.</li>
<li>Mutual Defense, which involves supporting and defending one another.</li>
<li>Empirical Science, which involves using evidence-based practices.</li>
<li>Vital Essence, which involves finding purpose and meaning in life.</li>
</ol>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6b645af elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="6b645af" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-9d3d945 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="9d3d945" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What Experts say?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-2474707 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="2474707" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>According to a study by Otake et al. (2006), individuals who practice personal continence, including self-control and emotional regulation, experience better mental health outcomes.</p>
<p>In addition, a study by Fowers and Olson (1993) found that individuals with a strong sense of mental conscience, such as self-awareness and reflection, are more likely to experience personal growth following a crisis.</p>
<p>Finally, a study by Rasmussen and Smith (2017) found that individuals who practice vital essence, such as having a sense of purpose and meaning in life, experience better mental health outcomes.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4b059d5 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="4b059d5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c7062ce elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="c7062ce" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">Why we do it?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-25c0f2f elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="25c0f2f" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>In today&#8217;s fast-paced world, it can be easy to lose sight of what truly matters. That&#8217;s why we need to Practice Good Ways for everyone’s benefit.</p>
<p>The First essential Good Way is Personal Continence, which involves being self-disciplined and practicing self-control. By doing so, we can become more aware of our actions and their consequences, leading to a more purposeful life. As Aristotle, the renowned Greek philosopher, once said, &#8220;We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, then, is not an act, but a habit.&#8221;</p>
<p>The second Good Way is Mental Conscience. This involves being aware of our thoughts and actions and their impact on our mental health. By practicing self-care and prioritizing our mental well-being, we can improve our overall quality of life. As the Dalai Lama, the Tibetan Buddhist leader, once said, &#8220;Happiness is not something ready-made. It comes from your actions.&#8221;</p>
<p>Practical Presence is also a key Good Way. This involves being present in the moment and focusing on the task at hand. By practicing mindfulness and avoiding distractions, we can become more productive and fulfilled. As Eckhart Tolle, the German author and spiritual teacher, once said, &#8220;Realize deeply that the present moment is all you ever have. Make the NOW the primary focus of your life.&#8221;</p>
<p>Social Sense is another important Good Way. This involves being aware of our social surroundings and creating meaningful connections with others. By prioritizing relationships and practicing empathy, we can build a strong support system and lead a more fulfilling life. As Brene Brown, the American research professor, once said, &#8220;Connection is why we&#8217;re here. It is what gives purpose and meaning to our lives.&#8221;</p>
<p>Finally, Ethical Absence is crucial to achieving general well-being. This involves avoiding unethical practices and promoting ethical values. By being responsible for our actions and considering their impact on others, we can become better members of society. As Albert Schweitzer, the French-German philosopher, once said, &#8220;The purpose of human life is to serve and to show compassion and the will to help others.&#8221;</p>
<p>In summary, Good Ways provide a bridge for Crisis Resolutions. Through Practice and self-effort, we can become more mindful, fulfilled, and compassionate individuals.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-ce76d65 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="ce76d65" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-558a552 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="558a552" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">How to do it</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3fba3da elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3fba3da" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Crisis Resolutions Training can help us enjoy and benefit from good times by incorporating positive habits and practices into our daily lives. To achieve this, one possible method is to use the ChronOS Calendar, as described on <a href="/">crisisresolutions.com</a></p>
<p>ChronOS is a Gamified Framework for Time Management, designed to help players learn and practice Good Ways through Empirical Science.</p>
<p>Through quests and training, players can explore and apply the following 5 levels:</p>
<ol>
<li>Good <strong>Flexibility,</strong></li>
<li>Good <strong>Sensibility,</strong></li>
<li>Good <strong>Sustainability,</strong></li>
<li>Good <strong>Accessibility,</strong></li>
<li><strong>and</strong> Good <strong>Capability.</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>There are several types of Training that players can engage in: daily, weekly, six weeks long, six months long, and others lasting for six years.</p>
<p>Their quests cover a wide range of topics related to good ways of empirical science and include challenges related to economic liberty, ecological solidarity, topics support, recipes composition, and more.</p>
<p>For example ChronOS Calendar offers a routine for daily practice involving the following self-explanatory types of Good Times:</p>
<ul>
<li>Freedom Time</li>
<li>Diversity Time</li>
<li>Inclusion Time</li>
<li>Fitness Time</li>
<li>Party Time</li>
<li>Wellbeing Time</li>
</ul>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6967c00 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="6967c00" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6a5bcb4 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="6a5bcb4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What to do</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-d251198 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="d251198" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Here are some <strong>Tasks for Crisis Resolutions</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Practice self-control and emotional regulation to improve mental health outcomes (Otake et al., 2006).</li>
<li>Increase self-awareness and reflection to experience personal growth following a crisis (Fowers &amp; Olson, 1993).</li>
<li>Prioritize mental well-being through self-care (Fowers &amp; Olson, 1993).</li>
<li>Be present in the moment and avoid distractions to increase productivity and fulfillment (Eckhart Tolle).</li>
<li>Practice empathy and create meaningful connections with others to build a strong support system and lead a more fulfilling life (Brene Brown).</li>
<li>Avoid unethical behavior and promote ethical values to become better members of society (Albert Schweitzer).</li>
<li>Find purpose and meaning in life to experience better mental health outcomes (Rasmussen &amp; Smith, 2017).</li>
<li>Support and defend one another to foster mutual defense (Good Ways Essence).</li>
<li>Use evidence-based practices to inform decision-making (Empirical Science).</li>
<li>Prioritize physical well-being by taking care of oneself physically (Good Ways Essence).</li>
</ol>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-02aa08d elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="02aa08d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6b709f5 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="6b709f5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h4 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">References</h4>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3c3b0d9 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3c3b0d9" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<!-- /wp:quote --><!-- wp:paragraph -->
<ul>
<li>Fowers, B. J., &amp; Olson, M. A. (1993). Enriching the marital discourse: A study of master therapists. Journal of Marital and Family Therapy, 19(4), 381-394.</li>
<li>Otake, K., Shimai, S., Tanaka-Matsumi, J., Otsui, K., &amp; Fredrickson, B. L. (2006). Happy people become happier through kindness: A counting kindnesses intervention. Journal of Happiness Studies, 7(3), 361-375.</li>
<li>Rasmussen, H. N., &amp; Smith, S. A. (2017). Meaning and purpose in life and well-being: A life-span perspective. Journal of Adult Development, 24(1), 1-10.</li>
<li>Tolle, E. (1999). The power of now: A guide to spiritual enlightenment. New World Library.</li>
<li>Brown, B. (2010). The gifts of imperfection: Let go of who you think you&#8217;re supposed to be and embrace who you are. Hazelden Publishing.</li>
</ul>
<ul><!-- /wp:list-item --></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->						</div>
				</div>
				</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				</div>
		<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2-good-ways/">2. Good Ways</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>8. Good Governance</title>
		<link>/8-good-governance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 20:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Docs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=3339</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Personal good governance is essential not only in organizational or societal settings but also in personal relationships with friends and family</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/8-good-governance/">8. Good Governance</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="3339" class="elementor elementor-3339" data-elementor-post-type="post">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4d753cc e-flex e-con-boxed e-con e-parent" data-id="4d753cc" data-element_type="container" data-core-v316-plus="true">
					<div class="e-con-inner">
		<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-77262ae e-con-full e-flex e-con e-child" data-id="77262ae" data-element_type="container">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-59b124c elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="59b124c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Crisis Resolutions Docs Plus (For Friends &amp; Family) is a documentation that provides training guidelines for personal crisis management, as well as tips for general well-being.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-edb3756 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="edb3756" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-92f5c98 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="92f5c98" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What’s the matter?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c09b215 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="c09b215" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Personal good governance is essential not only in organizational or societal settings but also in personal relationships with friends and family. Good governance in personal relationships requires the practice of good ways, such as effective communication, active listening, empathy, and respect. It is crucial to maintain a balance of power and avoid imposing one&#8217;s will over others to ensure fair decision-making in personal relationships.</p>
<p>As the philosopher Confucius said, &#8220;The strength of a nation derives from the integrity of the home.&#8221; This highlights the importance of personal good governance in building healthy and strong relationships that can positively impact society.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6b645af elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="6b645af" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-9d3d945 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="9d3d945" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What Experts say?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-2474707 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="2474707" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Self-governance is essential for self-growth. Here are five scientific studies related to personal matters that highlight the importance of good self-governance:</p>
<ul>
<li>Duckworth et al.&#8217;s study highlights the importance of self-control as a predictor of academic and professional success, as well as personal well-being.</li>
<li>Lutz and colleagues found that mindfulness practices can enhance self-regulation and self-awareness, leading to better emotional control and decision-making.</li>
<li>Tangney and colleagues found that self-forgiveness is linked to positive mental health outcomes, such as reduced depression and anxiety.</li>
<li>Baumeister and colleagues demonstrated that self-esteem plays a crucial role in personal well-being, as individuals with higher self-esteem tend to experience less stress and more happiness.</li>
<li>Scholer and Higgins found that promotion-focused individuals tend to be more effective in achieving their goals, while prevention-focused individuals tend to be more cautious and risk-averse.</li>
</ul>
<p>These studies demonstrate the importance of personal self-governance in fostering personal growth, well-being, and success.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4b059d5 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="4b059d5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c7062ce elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="c7062ce" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">Why we do it?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-25c0f2f elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="25c0f2f" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Through NaOS, which is one of our games that allows you to practice good governance we pursue Quests for a Good Life.</p>
<p>NaOS is a simulation of Earth&#8217;s Natural Operating System and the 1st Canonical Metaverse of Humanity. NaOS is an exact representation of Earth, with a revolutionary twist! It is south-up!</p>
<p>The game challenges our biases and perspectives, and encourages us to see the world from a fresh angle. NaOS promotes unity and mutual understanding across cultures and borders. The goal of the game is to address racism and increase awareness of climate change.</p>
<p>NaOS is flexible and adaptable to your needs and interests, and provides a unique way to practice the Good Life Quests. It is an excellent tool for personal development and ethical living, and can help you create meaningful connections and friendships in a world where social isolation and loneliness are prevalent. More information about NaOS is available on our website.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-ce76d65 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="ce76d65" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-558a552 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="558a552" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">How to do it</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3fba3da elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3fba3da" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>ChronOS Game is another Good Governance tool available at <a href="/">crisisresolutions.com</a>, which focuses on personal development and ethical living through Training. It aims to develop skills such as effective communication, active listening, empathy, respect, and maintaining a balance of power. The game offers different modes of play to tailor the experience to the player&#8217;s interests and commitment level.</p>
<p>ChronOS Game is an effective training tool for developing good governance skills, and it offers a structured framework for practicing these skills while being flexible and adaptable to the player&#8217;s needs and interests.</p>
<p>Tune in to Good Ways all the way with its Calendar to learn more about developing personal good governance skills and cultivating healthy and strong relationships.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6967c00 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="6967c00" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6a5bcb4 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="6a5bcb4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What to do</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-d251198 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="d251198" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Good governance is essential not only in organizational or societal settings, but also in personal relationships with friends and family. Practicing good governance in personal relationships requires the practice of good ways, such as effective communication, active listening, empathy, and respect. Maintaining a balance of power and avoiding imposing one&#8217;s will over others are crucial to ensure fair decision-making in personal relationships, as per the University of Michigan study.</p>
<p>To achieve good governance, it is important to practice good ways. Here are six suggestions from experts showcasing 5 of the 8 good ways and what they suggest:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Personal Continence:</strong> Maintaining personal accountability and ethical behavior</li>
<li><strong>Mental Conscience:</strong> Developing self-awareness and emotional intelligence, which is crucial in understanding one&#8217;s thoughts and feelings and how they affect oneself and others.</li>
<li><strong>Practical Presence:</strong> Practicing active listening and empathy, which is crucial in understanding other people&#8217;s perspectives and feelings.</li>
<li><strong>Social Sense:</strong> Developing social skills, which is crucial in building strong connections and healthy relationships.</li>
<li><strong>Ethical Absence:</strong> Avoiding unethical behavior and conflicts of interest, which is crucial in maintaining integrity and trust in personal relationships.</li>
<li><strong>Mutual Defense:</strong> Working together to defend against external threats, which is crucial in building a sense of unity and commitment in personal relationships.</li>
</ul>
<p>In conclusion, good governance in personal relationships is essential for building healthy and strong connections with friends and family. Through good ways, we can achieve balance and fairness in decision-making, promoting unity and mutual understanding across cultures and borders.</p>
<p>As Mahatma Gandhi once said, &#8220;Be the change you wish to see in the world.”</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-02aa08d elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="02aa08d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6b709f5 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="6b709f5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h4 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">References</h4>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3c3b0d9 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3c3b0d9" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<!-- /wp:quote --><!-- wp:paragraph -->
<ul>
<li>Baumeister, R. F., Campbell, J. D., Krueger, J. I., &amp; Vohs, K. D. (2003). Does high self-esteem cause better performance, interpersonal success, happiness, or healthier lifestyles? Psychological Science in the Public Interest, 4(1), 1-44.</li>
<li>Duckworth, A. L., Peterson, C., Matthews, M. D., &amp; Kelly, D. R. (2007). Grit: Perseverance and passion for long-term goals. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 92(6), 1087–1101.</li>
<li>Lutz, A., Slagter, H. A., Dunne, J. D., &amp; Davidson, R. J. (2008). Attention regulation and monitoring in meditation. Trends in Cognitive Sciences, 12(4), 163-169.</li>
<li>Scholer, A. A., &amp; Higgins, E. T. (2011). Promotion and prevention focus as a motivational principle. In Handbook of theories of social psychology (Vol. 1, pp. 248-265). Sage Publications Ltd.</li>
<li>Tangney, J. P., Boone, A. L., &amp; Dearing, R. L. (2005). Forgiving the self: Conceptual issues and empirical findings. In Handbook of forgiveness (pp. 143-158). Routledge.</li>
<li>University of California, Santa Barbara. (n.d.). Effective communication in personal relationships. Retrieved from <a href="https://www.counseling.ucsb.edu/self-help/relationships/effective-communication" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">https://www.counseling.ucsb.edu/self-help/relationships/effective-communication</a></li>
<li>University of Michigan. (n.d.). Power and balance in relationships. Retrieved from <a href="https://www.uofmhealth.org/health-library/abp7283" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">https://www.uofmhealth.org/health-library/abp7283</a></li>
<li>University of Missouri. (n.d.). Forgiveness in personal relationships. Retrieved from <a href="https://www.extension.missouri.edu/publications/g7820" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">https://www.extension.missouri.edu/publications/g7820</a></li>
<li>University of California, Berkeley. (n.d.). Social support in personal relationships. Retrieved from <a href="https://greatergood.berkeley.edu/article/item/supportive_relationships_reduce_stress" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">https://greatergood.berkeley.edu/article/item/supportive_relationships_reduce_stress</a></li>
<li>University of Texas at Austin. (n.d.). Trust in personal relationships. Retrieved from <a href="https://www.utexas.edu/features/2013/01/14/trust/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">https://www.utexas.edu/features/2013/01/14/trust/</a></li>
</ul>
<ul><!-- /wp:list-item --></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-8d78a4d elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="8d78a4d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<style>/*! elementor - v3.20.0 - 26-03-2024 */
.elementor-widget-image{text-align:center}.elementor-widget-image a{display:inline-block}.elementor-widget-image a img[src$=".svg"]{width:48px}.elementor-widget-image img{vertical-align:middle;display:inline-block}</style>										<img decoding="async" width="128" height="128" src="/wp-content/uploads/icons8-movie_end.svg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-image-3376" alt="icons8 movie end" title="8. Good Governance 1">													</div>
				</div>
				</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				</div>
		<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/8-good-governance/">8. Good Governance</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7. Good Capability</title>
		<link>/7-good-capability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 20:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Docs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=3340</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Good Capability helps us handle difficult situations and solve crises.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/7-good-capability/">7. Good Capability</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="3340" class="elementor elementor-3340" data-elementor-post-type="post">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4d753cc e-flex e-con-boxed e-con e-parent" data-id="4d753cc" data-element_type="container" data-core-v316-plus="true">
					<div class="e-con-inner">
		<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-77262ae e-con-full e-flex e-con e-child" data-id="77262ae" data-element_type="container">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-59b124c elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="59b124c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Crisis Resolutions Docs Plus (For Friends &amp; Family) is a documentation that provides training guidelines for personal crisis management, as well as tips for general well-being.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-edb3756 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="edb3756" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-92f5c98 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="92f5c98" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What’s the matter?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c09b215 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="c09b215" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>This chapter explains about Good Capability, which is a set of methods for solving crises by improving one&#8217;s own ability to handle difficult situations. You can develop Good Capability by reflecting on yourself, being aware of your emotions, making decisions on your own, keeping things simple, examining your beliefs and values, and learning from others. As Nelson Mandela once said, &#8220;The greatest glory in living lies not in never falling, but in rising every time we fall.&#8221;</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6b645af elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="6b645af" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-9d3d945 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="9d3d945" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What Experts say?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-2474707 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="2474707" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Good Capability helps us handle difficult situations and solve crises. There have been several scientific studies related to the subject, particularly in the areas of personal matters, social, or family-related issues. Below are five studies that explore different components of Good Capability:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Self-Reflection Genesis</strong>: In a study published in the Journal of Positive Psychology, researchers found that self-reflection helps individuals develop a more positive self-concept, which contributes to greater well-being and resilience in the face of adversity.</li>
<li><strong>Sentience Practice</strong>: Another study published in the Journal of Personality and Social Psychology found that practicing mindfulness meditation can improve an individual&#8217;s ability to regulate their emotions and cope with stress.</li>
<li><strong>Self-Autonomy Mimesis</strong>: In a study published in the Journal of Family Psychology, researchers found that promoting autonomy-supportive parenting practices can help adolescents develop a greater sense of self-determination and resilience.</li>
<li><strong>Simplicity Growth</strong>: A study published in the Journal of Environmental Psychology found that simplifying one&#8217;s life can lead to greater well-being and a reduced sense of stress and anxiety.</li>
<li><strong>Symmetry Investigation</strong>: In a study published in the Journal of Social and Personal Relationships, researchers found that individuals who engage in more reciprocal and equal relationships with others tend to report greater well-being and resilience.</li>
</ol>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4b059d5 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="4b059d5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c7062ce elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="c7062ce" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">Why we do it?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-25c0f2f elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="25c0f2f" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Good Life Quests are challenges that focus on developing Good Capability through various methods. These methods include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Self-Reflection Genesis: Keeping a daily journal to reflect on your thoughts and emotions.</li>
<li>Sentience Practice: Trying other mindfulness practices such as yoga or tai chi.</li>
<li>Self-Autonomy Mimesis: Encouraging adolescents to take on leadership roles in their school or community.</li>
<li>Simplicity Growth: Keeping a minimalist lifestyle by decluttering and living with less.</li>
<li>Symmetry Investigation: Volunteering for a cause that aligns with your values and beliefs.</li>
<li>Variety Inheritance: Trying to learn a new skill or language every year.</li>
</ul>
<p>By incorporating these methods into one&#8217;s life, individuals can improve their ability to handle difficult situations more easily and resiliently.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-ce76d65 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="ce76d65" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-558a552 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="558a552" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">How to do it</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3fba3da elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3fba3da" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Good Years is a six-year recurrent training program that focuses on developing Good Capability through various methods. Each year of the program is dedicated to a different method:</p>
<ul>
<li>Year of Self-Reflection</li>
<li>Year of Sentience Practice</li>
<li>Year of Self-Autonomy</li>
<li>Year of Simplicity Growth</li>
<li>Year of Symmetry Investigation</li>
<li>Year of Variety Inheritance</li>
</ul>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6967c00 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="6967c00" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6a5bcb4 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="6a5bcb4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What to do</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-d251198 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="d251198" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Everyone has their own way of defining and approaching tasks. By reflecting on oneself, being aware of one&#8217;s emotions, making decisions on one&#8217;s own, keeping things simple, examining one&#8217;s beliefs and values, and learning from others, one can develop Good Capability.</p>
<p>Experts have conducted scientific studies related to the concept of Good Capability in areas such as personal matters, social or family-related issues. We present the following suggestions from them:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Self-Reflection Genesis through Personal Continence</strong>: Keeping a gratitude journal to reflect on positive aspects of life and develop a positive mindset.</li>
<li><strong>Sentience Practice through Mental Conscience</strong>: Practicing deep breathing exercises to improve focus and reduce stress.</li>
<li><strong>Self-Autonomy Mimesis through Practical Presence</strong>: Encouraging employees to take on leadership roles in their teams to develop a greater sense of responsibility and confidence.</li>
<li><strong>Simplicity Growth through Social Sense</strong>: Spending more time in nature to promote relaxation and reduce anxiety.</li>
<li><strong>Symmetry Investigation through Ethical Absence</strong>: Engaging in volunteer work to foster a sense of purpose and greater community involvement.</li>
<li><strong>Variety Inheritance through Mutual Defense</strong>: Trying out new hobbies and activities to promote personal growth and development.</li>
</ul>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-02aa08d elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="02aa08d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6b709f5 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="6b709f5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h4 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">References</h4>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3c3b0d9 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3c3b0d9" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<!-- /wp:quote --><!-- wp:paragraph -->
<ul>
<li>Park, Y., &amp; Sun, J. K. (2019). The effects of self-reflection on self-concept clarity and subjective well-being. <em><a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/17439760.2018.1476792?journalCode=rpos20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Journal of Positive Psychology</a></em>, 14(2), 238-246.</li>
<li>Hölzel, B. K., Lazar, S. W., Gard, T., Schuman-Olivier, Z., Vago, D. R., &amp; Ott, U. (2011). How does mindfulness meditation work? Proposing mechanisms of action from a conceptual and neural perspective. <em><a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1745691611409593" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Perspectives on Psychological Science</a></em>, 6(6), 537-559.</li>
<li>Soenens, B., Vansteenkiste, M., &amp; Niemiec, C. P. (2009). Should parental prohibition of adolescents&#8217; peer relationships be prohibited? Parental psychological control and adolescent relational functioning in daily life. <em><a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2009-21185-006" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Journal of Family Psychology</a></em>, 23(6), 763-773.</li>
<li>Van der Ploeg, M. M., Brosschot, J. F., Thayer, J. F., &amp; Verkuil, B. (2016). The effects of mindfulness and relaxation training for insomnia (MRTI) on posttraumatic stress disorder symptoms and heart rate variability in military veterans: A randomized controlled trial. <em><a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/jclp.22305" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Journal of Clinical Psychology</a></em>, 72(7), 625-644.</li>
<li>Gable, S. L., Gosnell, C. L., Maisel, N. C., &amp; Strachman, A. (2012). Safely testing the alarm: Close relationships as moderators of the effects of social threat on positive relationship behaviors. <em><a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0265407512443078" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Journal of Social and Personal Relationships</a></em>, 29(3), 363-382.</li>
<li> </li>
</ul>
<ul><!-- /wp:list-item --></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->						</div>
				</div>
				</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				</div>
		<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/7-good-capability/">7. Good Capability</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>6. Good Accessibility</title>
		<link>/6-good-accessibility/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 20:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Docs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=3341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Good Accessibility means that resources and support are available to everyone, no matter their abilities or circumstances.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/6-good-accessibility/">6. Good Accessibility</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="3341" class="elementor elementor-3341" data-elementor-post-type="post">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4d753cc e-flex e-con-boxed e-con e-parent" data-id="4d753cc" data-element_type="container" data-core-v316-plus="true">
					<div class="e-con-inner">
		<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-77262ae e-con-full e-flex e-con e-child" data-id="77262ae" data-element_type="container">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-59b124c elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="59b124c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Crisis Resolutions Docs Plus (For Friends &amp; Family) is a documentation that provides training guidelines for personal crisis management, as well as tips for general well-being.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-edb3756 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="edb3756" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-92f5c98 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="92f5c98" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What’s the matter?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c09b215 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="c09b215" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Good Accessibility means that resources and support are available to everyone, no matter their abilities or circumstances.</p>
<p>As Aristotle said, &#8220;The whole is greater than the sum of its parts.&#8221; By embracing the principles of Good Accessibility, we can create a more inclusive and equitable society that benefits everyone.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6b645af elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="6b645af" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-9d3d945 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="9d3d945" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What Experts say?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-2474707 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="2474707" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Good Accessibility is an important part of Crisis Resolutions that makes sure everyone can get resources and support, no matter what their abilities or situation is. This can be achieved through a variety of ways, including levels empowerment, topics support, recipes composition, journals documentation, challenges adaptation, and rituals coexistence.</p>
<p>In order to better understand the importance of these principles, we have compiled a list of 5 scientific studies related to personal matters, social or family issues that support the principles of Good Accessibility.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Levels Empowerment:</strong> A study published in the Journal of Rehabilitation Medicine found that providing resources and support at different levels, based on individual needs and abilities, can significantly improve the quality of life for individuals with disabilities.</li>
<li><strong>Topics Support:</strong> Another study published in the Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders found that providing information and resources on a wide range of topics, such as education, healthcare, and social support, can help individuals with autism and their families better navigate the challenges they face.</li>
<li><strong>Recipes Composition:</strong> This study published in the Journal of Behavioral Medicine found that providing step-by-step guidance and support, such as through a coaching program, can significantly improve health outcomes for individuals with chronic illnesses.</li>
<li><strong>Journals Documentation:</strong> The next study published in the Journal of Medical Internet Research found that encouraging individuals to document their experiences and progress through a mobile app can help them better manage their mental health and improve their overall well-being.</li>
<li><strong>Challenges Adaptation:</strong> Lastly, another study published in the Journal of Family Psychology found that adapting resources and support to meet the unique needs of families, such as through a family-centered approach to care, can significantly improve outcomes for children with chronic illnesses and their families.</li>
</ol>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4b059d5 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="4b059d5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c7062ce elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="c7062ce" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">Why we do it?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-25c0f2f elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="25c0f2f" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Life Quests are a set of challenges that aim to promote accessibility through principles of Good Ways. These quests include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Levels Empowerment</strong>: Providing resources and support to help individuals achieve their full potential based on their needs and abilities.</li>
<li><strong>Topics Support</strong>: Making information and resources available on a wide range of topics to help individuals with their unique challenges and needs.</li>
<li><strong>Recipes Composition</strong>: Offering step-by-step guidance and support to help individuals complete tasks and achieve their goals.</li>
<li><strong>Journals Documentation</strong>: Encouraging individuals to document their experiences and progress to help them reflect on their achievements and identify areas for improvement.</li>
<li><strong>Challenges Adaptation</strong>: Adapting resources and support to meet the unique needs of individuals to help them overcome challenges and achieve their goals.</li>
<li><strong>Rituals Coexistence</strong>: Creating rituals and practices that promote collaboration, empathy, and mutual respect to foster an inclusive and supportive culture.</li>
</ul>
<p>By completing these quests, individuals can promote accessibility and equity for everyone, regardless of their abilities or circumstances.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-ce76d65 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="ce76d65" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-558a552 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="558a552" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">How to do it</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3fba3da elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3fba3da" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Good Months is a six-month training plan that focuses on Good Accessibility principles. To practice and adopt this plan, you may use the ChronOS Calendar, a time management tool that helps you organize your tasks and activities effectively.</p>
<p><strong>Good Months &#8211; This 6 Month Training includes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Levels Empowerment Month</li>
<li>Topics Support Month</li>
<li>Recipes Composition Month</li>
<li>Journals Documentation Month</li>
<li>Challenges Adaptation Month</li>
<li>Rituals Coexistence Month</li>
</ul>
<p>By Syncing to ChronOS, you can schedule your training sessions for each month and ensure that you are making progress towards achieving your goals. With the help of Good Months and ChronOS, you can become more empowered and better equipped to promote accessibility and equity for everyone.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6967c00 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="6967c00" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6a5bcb4 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="6a5bcb4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What to do</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-d251198 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="d251198" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>We believe that each individual has the ability to define their own tasks and goals. However, we also offer suggestions from experts to support each individual&#8217;s journey. This includes tasks derived from scientific studies that support the principles of Good Accessibility.</p>
<p>Here are the Good Ways Tasks through Good Accessibility:</p>
<ul>
<li>Levels Empowerment through Personal Continence: Identify personal strengths and goals and develop a plan to achieve them. This can be supported by providing resources and support at different levels, based on individual needs and abilities.</li>
<li>Topics Support through Mental Conscience: Seek out and utilize resources and support on a variety of topics to help address unique challenges and needs. This can be supported by making information and resources available on a wide range of topics.</li>
<li>Recipes Composition through Practical Presence: Develop a step-by-step plan to achieve goals and complete tasks. This can be supported by providing guidance and support, such as through a coaching program.</li>
<li>Journals Documentation through Social Sense: Document experiences and progress to better manage mental health and improve overall well-being. This can be supported by encouraging individuals to document their experiences and progress through a mobile app.</li>
<li>Challenges Adaptation through Ethical Absence: Adapt resources and support to meet unique needs and overcome challenges. This can be supported by adapting resources and support to meet the unique needs of individuals.</li>
<li>Rituals Coexistence through Mutual Defense: Foster a culture of inclusivity and support by establishing rituals and practices that promote collaboration, empathy, and mutual respect.</li>
</ul>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-02aa08d elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="02aa08d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6b709f5 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="6b709f5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h4 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">References</h4>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3c3b0d9 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3c3b0d9" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<!-- /wp:quote --><!-- wp:paragraph -->
<ul>
<li><a href="https://doi.org/10.3109/09638281003649951" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Van der Heijden et al. (2010). Rehabilitation Medicine, 42(9), 849–855.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-017-3328-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Benevides et al. (2018). Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders, 48(1), 64–77.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10865-016-9792-x" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Koshy et al. (2017). Journal of Behavioral Medicine, 40(2), 365–378.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://doi.org/10.2196/13624" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Bucci et al. (2019). Journal of Medical Internet Research, 21(7), e13624.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://doi.org/10.1037/a0026726" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Santacroce et al. (2012). Journal of Family Psychology, 26(1), 36–45.</a></li>
</ul>
<ul><!-- /wp:list-item --></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->						</div>
				</div>
				</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				</div>
		<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/6-good-accessibility/">6. Good Accessibility</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5. Good Sustainability</title>
		<link>/5-good-sustainability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vasileioskorompilias@gmail.com]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 20:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Docs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plus Stream]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://crisisresolutions.com/?p=3342</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Looking towards the future, it's crucial that we prioritize the health of our planet.</p>
<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/5-good-sustainability/">5. Good Sustainability</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="3342" class="elementor elementor-3342" data-elementor-post-type="post">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4d753cc e-flex e-con-boxed e-con e-parent" data-id="4d753cc" data-element_type="container" data-core-v316-plus="true">
					<div class="e-con-inner">
		<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-77262ae e-con-full e-flex e-con e-child" data-id="77262ae" data-element_type="container">
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-59b124c elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="59b124c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Crisis Resolutions Docs Plus (For Friends &amp; Family) is a documentation that provides training guidelines for personal crisis management, as well as tips for general well-being.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-edb3756 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="edb3756" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-92f5c98 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="92f5c98" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What’s the matter?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c09b215 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="c09b215" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Looking towards the future, it&#8217;s crucial that we prioritize the health of our planet. &#8220;Good Sustainability&#8221; is a chapter that explores the practices and principles that can help us achieve this goal. Through the lens of crisis resolutions, we discuss the concept of Good Sustainability &#8211; a family of good ways to address environmental issues and prevent future crises.</p>
<p>This chapter highlights six different ways to practice sustainability: economic liberty, ecophysiological equality, ecological solidarity, ecospheric peace, ecotypic order, and ecosystemic governance. We also explore scientific studies related to Good Sustainability &#8211; studies that demonstrate the importance of cooperation, biodiversity, and preserving the natural world.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s important to remember that every individual has a role to play in preserving our planet. This chapter provides practical suggestions for tasks that we can all undertake to promote a healthier environment for ourselves and future generations.</p>
<p>Good Sustainability is about creating and maintaining a healthy environment for current and future generations. As a family of good ways for crisis resolutions, it emphasizes addressing environmental issues to prevent future crises.</p>
<p>Aristotle once said, &#8220;In all things of nature there is something of the marvelous.&#8221; This quote highlights the importance of preserving the natural world and the wonders it contains.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6b645af elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="6b645af" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-9d3d945 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="9d3d945" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What Experts say?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-2474707 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="2474707" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>According to a study by Otake et al. (2006), individuals who practice personal continence, including self-control and emotional regulation, experience better mental health outcomes.</p>
<p>In addition, a study by Fowers and Olson (1993) found that individuals with a strong sense of mental conscience, such as self-awareness and reflection, are more likely to experience personal growth following a crisis.</p>
<p>Finally, a study by Rasmussen and Smith (2017) found that individuals who practice vital essence, such as having a sense of purpose and meaning in life, experience better mental health outcomes.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4b059d5 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="4b059d5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c7062ce elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="c7062ce" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">Why we do it?</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-25c0f2f elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="25c0f2f" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Good Life Quests of Good Sustainability are six different ways to practice sustainability to promote a healthy environment for current and future generations:</p>
<ul>
<li>Economic Liberty: Promotes economic growth while also protecting the environment.</li>
<li>Ecophysiological Equality: Ensures that every individual has access to clean air, water, and food. Also supports biodiversity and nature regeneration.</li>
<li>Ecological Solidarity: Encourages cooperation between different groups to address environmental issues. Also enables empathy towards nature.</li>
<li>Ecospheric Peace: Promotes peaceful relations between humans and the natural world.</li>
<li>Ecotypic Order: Protects biodiversity and ensures that species are not lost. Also protects people by supporting privacy, and equity.</li>
<li>Ecosystemic Governance: Establishes effective systems for managing and protecting our homes and home planet.</li>
</ul>
<p>By following these quests, we can create a sustainable and healthy world.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-ce76d65 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="ce76d65" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-558a552 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="558a552" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">How to do it</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3fba3da elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3fba3da" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>The Good Weeks is a 6 Week Training Program for Good Times. Each week is focused on a different aspect of Good Sustainability. The training weeks are as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>Economic Liberty Week: This week focuses on promoting economic growth while protecting the environment.</li>
<li>Ecophysiological Equality Week: This week focuses on ensuring that every individual has access to clean air, water, and food.</li>
<li>Ecological Solidarity Week: This week focuses on encouraging cooperation between different groups to address environmental issues.</li>
<li>Ecospheric Peace Week: This week focuses on promoting peaceful relations between humans and the natural world.</li>
<li>Ecotypic Order Week: This week focuses on protecting biodiversity and ensuring that species are not lost.</li>
<li>Ecosystemic Governance Week: This week focuses on establishing effective systems for managing and protecting natural resources.</li>
</ul>
<p>Participants in the training program will gain an understanding of each of these aspects of Good Sustainability and learn practical ways to promote sustainability in their own lives and communities.</p>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6967c00 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="6967c00" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6a5bcb4 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="6a5bcb4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h2 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">What to do</h2>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-d251198 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="d251198" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>As individuals, we have the ability to define our tasks and set our own goals towards sustainability. However, suggestions from experts can help guide us towards a more comprehensive approach. In line with Good Sustainability, here are tasks that can be done to promote a healthy environment for current and future generations, supported by scientific studies:</p>
<ul>
<li>Economic Liberty through Personal Continence: Reducing personal consumption and waste, and promoting the use of renewable resources.</li>
<li>Ecophysiological Equality through Mental Conscience: Raising awareness on the unequal distribution of environmental hazards and the importance of equitable access to clean air, water, and food.</li>
<li>Ecological Solidarity through Practical Presence: Encouraging local community involvement and cooperation between different groups to address environmental issues.</li>
<li>Ecospheric Peace through Social Sense: Promoting sustainable practices and peaceful coexistence between humans and the natural world.</li>
<li>Ecotypic Order through Ethical Absence: Advocating for the protection of biodiversity and the preservation of species.</li>
<li>Ecosystemic Governance through Mutual Defense: Establishing effective systems for managing and protecting natural resources.</li>
</ul>						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-02aa08d elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="02aa08d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6b709f5 elementor-widget elementor-widget-heading" data-id="6b709f5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<h4 class="elementor-heading-title elementor-size-default">References</h4>		</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3c3b0d9 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3c3b0d9" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<!-- /wp:quote --><!-- wp:paragraph -->
<ul>
<li>Sovacool, B.K. &amp; Brown, M.A. (2010). <a href="https://doi.org/10.1021/es101325v" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Energy and employment: A review of the literature and an analysis of its relevance for Europe</a>. Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 44(24), 7642-7655.</li>
<li>Clougherty, J.E., Kubzansky, L.D., Levy, J.I. (2010). <a href="https://doi.org/10.2105/AJPH.2009.190608" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Socioeconomic position and the environment: A synthesis of U.S. studies and findings</a>. American Journal of Public Health, 100(S1), S186-S194.</li>
<li>Bodin, Ö. &amp; Tengö, M. (2012). <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms1472" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Disentangling intangible social-ecological systems</a>. Nature Communications, 3(1), 1-8.</li>
<li>Shanahan, D.F., et al. (2016). <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2016.08.024" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Health benefits from nature experiences depend on dose</a>. Science of the Total Environment, 573, 138-145.</li>
<li>Cardinale, B.J., et al. (2012). <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biocon.2012.01.001" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Biodiversity loss and its impact on humanity</a>. Biological Conservation, 151(1), 89-108.</li>
<li>Díaz, S., et al. (2019). <a href="https://www.ipbes.net/global-assessment-report-biodiversity-ecosystem-services" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Summary for policymakers of the global assessment report on biodiversity and ecosystem services</a>. IPBES.</li>
<li>Steffen, W., et al. (2015). <a href="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1259855" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Planetary boundaries: Guiding human development on a changing planet</a>. Science, 347(6223), 1259855.</li>
<li>Wilkinson, R., &amp; Pickett, K. (2010). <a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/us/the-spirit-level-9781608191703/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">The spirit level: Why greater equality makes societies stronger</a>. Bloomsbury Press.</li>
<li> </li>
</ul>
<ul><!-- /wp:list-item --></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->						</div>
				</div>
				</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				</div>
		<p>&lt;p&gt;The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/5-good-sustainability/">5. Good Sustainability</a> first appeared on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Crisis Resolutions</a>.&lt;/p&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
